A day of enjoyable food

Day 00817: Thursday, 2017 June 01

General news

I haven't had pancakes in forever, and decided to make some for breakfast. I think I'll try to do that more often. I'm still not sure I like this frying pan being porous, but I suppose it's fine as long as the pan's only used for plant-based foods. Porous cooking surfaces seem unsanitary to me though. I also haven't had salad in ages, so I had that for lunch and dinner. I had a nice blend of salad mix, chopped green onion, nutritional yeast, lemon dill seasoning, lemon juice, and Italian dressing. On my dinner salad, I also had a chopped pickle. The salads were quite delicious! I'm going to run out of that lemon dill seasoning though. It's got a lot of salt, so once I run out, I won't be replacing it. After all, I'm trying to eat more healthful meals.

After breakfast, I picked up the cashier's cheque I needed, then after lunch, I used it to pay rent. Later, the on-site manager's parent stopped by my apartment. The on-site manager and their parent had just gone grocery shopping, had cleaned out their freezer, and thought I might be able to use the food. That was nice of them! They brought frozen cherries, a frozen dinner, and ground turkey. I obviously couldn't eat the turkey, and the dinner was meat-based as well. The cherries are pretty cool though. I wonder what I'll use them in.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

I took one final exam today, then finalised my learning journal entries and submitted them. Tomorrow, I should take the other final exam. After that, schools out for me for over a week! I'm hoping the university fixes my name in their system by the time school's back in session. I'd prefer to start off the coming term as me.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My ID arrived

Day 00818: Friday, 2017 June 02

General news

I cut up a green onion and added that to the pancake mix for this morning's breakfast. That turned out pretty well.

I think my abdominal muscles are slightly stronger than before. Either that, or I'm being less of a baby about sit-ups. I was able to make it to my daily goal of ten sit-ups without any real difficulty, so I've upped it to twenty sit-ups. I barely made it to that goal. If I keep the goal barely in reach though, maybe I can stop being so fat.

My DMV ID arrived in the mail. I'm so excited! Now, in most situations, there's no need for my birth name to ever be spoken. I can be me, and no one will question it.

I got in touch with the banker today about finishing my account, but it seems that will no longer be necessary. The offer they gave me was only valid for people that have never had an account with that bank before. I opened and closed an account with them back when I was in Coos Bay, so there's no point in opening the account now. Darn. I could've used the $75 USD they had said they'd give me.

I tried to get my Discover account updated today too. However, Discover wanted a copy of my new ID and the court order, but wouldn't allow me to upload them. Their system said the files were too large. I've explained the issue and asked Discover what they want me to do. When I hear back, we'll see if I keep the account open. I suspect they'll ask me to mail my documents to them. However, their website says they only accept original documents, not copies. The court kept the original copy of the court order. I suspect Discover would accept certified copies, but the court doesn't just give those away. I'm not biking to Eugene to buy another copy to send to Discover unless Discover plans to reimburse me both for postage and for the copy itself. I won't ask for compensation of my time though, I'll just call that exercises and claim I'm doing it to try to lose some stomach fat. Still, I don't think Discover will offer to reimburse me for anything, even though it's their own system that's not allowing me to upload the files. I could be getting ahead of myself though. I expect the worst, but I haven't even given Discover a chance yet. I should wait until they respond before jumping to conclusions about what they'll expect of me.

My shift leader gave my documents to our head manager as promised. Was I early enough to get the name fixed on my upcoming pay cheque? I'll find out in three days. The head manager corrected my name on the digital time clock today before I clocked in though, and said they've corrected it on the schedule. I forgot to actually check the schedule for next week's shifts though.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

I didn't end up taking the second final exam today. I'll probably take it tomorrow.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Complications in minestats

Day 00819: Saturday, 2017 June 03

General news

I couldn't make it past eighteen sit-ups this morning. I had the will, but not the strength. Still, the first eleven were pretty easy, so I'm sticking to my initial assessment that I'm getting a little stronger. After resting a while and getting my final exam taken, I went back and completed the last two sit-ups.

I found a futon out by the street with a sign saying people can take it. I considered taking it myself, but I'm not so desperate for furniture at this point. I'm not sure I even want a futon, and I already have a couch to sit on. If it's still there, I might pick it up later, but it's awfully heavy, so I probably won't.

I set out to fix the bug in minestats that makes it sometimes, but not usually, count immature farm plants as minerals. The problem isn't the counting, obviously, but the *inconsistent* counting. However, there are legitimate times when the farm plants should definitely not count as minerals, which is actually most of the time, and my mod gets that right. So now, for consistency, I need to make it never count farm plants. I can see in the code how to do that. It'd be ridiculously easy. However, looking at the structure of the item drop tables ... It looks like there's another bug that'd be exposed by the fix. It's sort of obscure, but would still result in some nodes being inconsistently counted as minerals. I don't know of any in-circulation mods that'd trigger this error, and the default game doesn't. However, it would be poor practice not to seal up this hole.

My boss says the name on my upcoming pay cheque hasn't been updated, but my name on all pay cheques after that should be. It's a good thing I've kept one credit union in the dark about the change then! I'll deposit the pay cheque, then wait fifteen days for the next pay cheque. If my name's truly been updated on it, I'll let the credit union know to update my account.

After work, I found the paperwork from Chase Bank in my mailbox. It's ... confusing though. It says Chase needs the documentation of the change that I brought in the other day, and if my name change isn't because of a court order, they additionally need me to fill out the form they sent. So ... if it is because of a court order (and it is), I *don't* need to fill out the form? So why'd they need to send it to me before they'd help me? They won't be open tomorrow, but I'll ask them about it on Monday.

Discover didn't read my question on how to transmit my documents to them when their website won't let me upload them. They simply replied requesting that I upload the documents. Ugh! I've replied in an annoyed tone:

You *CLEARLY* didn't actually read my message. I *TRIED* to upload my documents, but the Discover website *WON'T LET ME*. It says the files are too large. So I'll ask again: what do you want me to do? How can I get the files to you? I have a scan of both my new ID and the court order on my computer. If need be, I can get a scan of the Social Security card too. However, your website won't let me upload them. How would you like me to send you the files?

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

I took my final final exam for the term. I have mixed feelings about how well/poorly I did, but I won't find out the results for a while.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

32-bit integers!

Day 00820: Sunday, 2017 June 04

General news

I began the morning preparing to do laundry, but I quickly realised I wanted to clean the sinks with my dirty dish towel before washing it. The kitchen sink was full of dishes, and I'm kind of tired of washing them by hand. I took a trip to Fred Meyer to get dish washer soap, and found some nice, eco-friendly powder. With the dishes loaded up, I scrubbed out both sinks, then started laundry.

While the laundry machines did their thing, I worked on programming the bug fix for minestats. While I was at it, I almost-entirely rewrote the mod. I needed some code to be run after all mods had loaded, but before any players acted, so I looked for an API function I'm almost certain I saw used in a subgame. If I recall, it took a function as an argument, then ran that function right before the map generator was set up. I searched through the properties and functions contained in the minetest table, but I never could find that function. Instead though, I found a function for retrieving a mod-specific data storage object. I looked into the documentation on it, and it's got the option of storing integer data, not just strings like what I've been using. I tested it out with the numbers 99999999999999 and -99999999999999, the highest and lowest integers that Lua will correctly store as strings, along with the numbers just out of bounds, 100000000000000 and -100000000000000. I needed to know how the integer storage would handle these numbers. Would real integer storage allow me to transcend the limits of Lua number strings? As it turned out, no it did not. The results I got were kind of strange, too, and I didn't understand them at first. 99999999999999 got changed into a shorter number with seemingly-random digits. So the integer had less bits and it had hit its limit and stopped. There had to be dome sort of cap, right? Wrong! 100000000000000 had been translated into the number one higher than 99999999999999 had been. -99999999999999 and -100000000000000 had been translated to the negative versions of those same two numbers. I did some experimenting to try to find the threshold, and found that when the numbers I tried to store were in certain ranges, their signs flipped. The integers were looping! I decided to pull out my Galculator so find likely thresholds, and tried 2^32 and -2^32. Both were stored as zero. I'd found my boundaries!

Or, I suppose, not my boundaries, but my loop size. There's no limit, it just goes on forever. It's awesome! In a few minutes of spare time one day, I'd already implemented that same sort of looping into my use of the Lua number strings, though I hadn't gotten a chance to commit that to the repo' yet. Now, I had that same looping, but in a more natural way in my code (simply allowing the integer to wrap itself instead of testing the value of the integer before deciding to either increment or send to the far negative). Additionally, 32-bit integers are just so much cooler and geekier than signed, 14-digit, base-10 numbers, even if the 32-bit numbers have less storage potential. This is absolutely fantastic! I'm so excited. The 32-bit integers are signed, but in cases where I need to know the value of the integer (as opposed to simply incriminating it), I unfold it to be unsigned, with a maximum value of 4294967295. No one should reach the limit in my mod.

As I said, I did a nearly-total rewrite of the mod. The mod now shows the player all minerals that can be collected before they've found them. This lets players know what to look for, and also lets mod developers and server administrators very quickly test to see if their mods are supported. Minerals are also displayed in alphabetical order (by internal name, not player-facing name), not in order of which minerals a player has the most of. This provides consistent ordering. When mineral-defining mods are removed, the minerals they defined are no longer displayed as unknown items on the stats page, either. They're immediately hidden (though their data isn't removed, in case the mod is reinstalled later). If no minerals are defined, the stats page becomes hidden from all players. Support for unified_inventory has been dropped. unified_inventory is too inflexible for full support, so I implemented partial support before. Partial support makes my mod look broken though, so I'm done with that. unified_inventory is an ugly mess, both in how it works and in how it looks. I'm done with it. Everything's in working order, with one exception. The old database format is no longer used. I need to build code to read the old files, then add their data to the new database. Until I do that, I can't commit to the repo', as it'll break stuff for people that used an old version of my mod. I can do that, then remove the data from the files, but there are a couple of problems. First, I can't get a list of the existing files, each of which is named after a player. I have to wait until that player logs in, check to see if they have an old database file, then read it and update the main database. The second issue is that I can't remove the old files or the old directory. If I was writing a program, I could do it, but instead, I'm working from within Minetest's sandbox.

I forgot to change out of my work shoes until it was too late. The head manager was speeding things up, and brought my bike out from the back room. Normally, I'd go back there to get it, and switch back to my street shoes while I was back there. It threw me off a little, and I forgot to change shoes until the manager had set the alarm and locked us both out. Oh, well. I'll get my street shoes back tomorrow.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I thought I was done, but I am not.

Day 00821: Monday, 2017 June 05

General news

cheapie on #Minetest told me about minetest.get_dir_list(), a function that'll get me the list of database files to convert all at once! I still need a way to delete the old files, but that's less important. The Settings(file_name):remove(key) method is supposed to delete a key/value pair from the file, but it seems to be no-op, or something. I was going to remove each key/value pair as I finished with it. I ended up having to use io.open(file_name, "w"):close() at the end to erase everything at once instead. Either way, it accomplishes the same task though: removing the key/value pairs so they won't be re-imported a second time.

I thought I'd finished up the mod today, but not so much. First, when testing, I found a corner case I hadn't anticipated: legacy and otherwise nonstandard item strings. My mod doesn't handle them properly. I need to go back and fix that at some point. It should be easy with a simple normalisation. I've also found a way to differentiate things such as coral from things such as cobble. Stone can be "crafted"! I can run a check in my mod to see if a node is craftable. If so, don't count it, if not, do. Supporting coral in this way comes with supporting the harvest of saplings and seeds, too. I'd love to have support for these anyway though, just because it balances out the count a bit. In its current state, minestats is biased towards miners. Surface-dwellers are neglected. With support for some plants, people are encouraged both to play underground and in the sunlight. One issue could come up though, which is that in the other mod, minequest, automated support for counted nodes and their derivatives would unintuitively not include wooden items. Technically, an ABM converts saplings into trees, you don't craft trees from them.

At first, it seemed that supporting these new nodes would require introducing some ugly side effects to my mod's functionality. Things such as lit furnaces and open chests (Minetest now has an "open" version of the chest nodes, used when someone accesses their inventory) would end up on the stats page. I tried to rationalise it, too. I mean, players couldn't very well harvest open chests on their own, but it two people worked together, it would be possible, right? Someone might want to do it just so their stats page would say they had. I also thought about checking to see not only if the node was craftable (open chests are not), but also if the drop was craftable. However, ruling out open chests and lit furnaces based on the craftability of their drop would also rule out mese, coal, and diamonds, three of the base eight I most want counted. I could try checking for presence in the not_in_creative_inventory group, which would almost certainly rule out a bunch of stuff that shouldn't be counted, but that'd be hacky. Besides, it would mean admitting the problem wasn't actually solvable; that I need a user-specified flag to tell my mod what should and should not be considered worth counting. Relying on such a flag would mean throwing in the towel. No. There will be none of that.

However, it turns out that open chests are not only not diggable, they're also poorly programmed. First, there's the fact that their definition includes what item they drop when dug, but are defined to not be diggable. This is ridiculous, and causes a false positive in my mod. The fact that they're undiggable means more than ever though that I need to remove them from the stats page. Otherwise, the impossible-to-earn stat just sits there and taunts users. But that should be a defining quality I can use to blacklist the open chests, right? Yes and no. A node that can never be dug should have its diggable property set to false. However, the open chests have it set to true. Instead, they define their can_dig method to always return false. This means I can't weed them out based on never being diggable, despite the fact that they're not digabble. Instead, I have to weed them out based on the fact that they aren't necessarily diggable always, but very well could be. For my current use case, that's fine. It lets me rule out lit furnaces too, which to be honest, makes my mod's output look so much cleaner. Also, anything that defines a can_dig method is likely unnatural. These nodes will either be implementation artefacts, such as is the case with the lit furnace, or will be already ruled out because they're craftable, like the unlit furnace. However, it's still a poor and non-semantic design choice on the part of whoever coded the open chests.

In addition to these other features I want to add, I also want to add support for nodes that drop multiple of the same item. Some testing shows the Minetest formspec API is up for the task, so with a little more normalisation, I should have that working. However, nodes that drop multiple different types of items in the same drop won't be supported (at least not with first-class stats) as I don't have a proper way to represent this condition in the database or especially on the stats page. I might support them with second-class stats though, allowing people to track their farming activities though.

I headed to Chase Bank again to speak with a banker about the paperwork and ask what to do. I ended up speaking with the same banker as before. Again. Are they the only banker in the branch? Not that I mind though, after the first repeat. It was embarrassing to have to admit I was Alex all along, but today, having them know what was going on already sped up the process. The person instructing them over the telephone had told them last time that I needed to fill out paperwork sent to my address, so they were in the same boat as me as far as not being sure why I was sent what I was. They asked someone over the telephone again, and it sounds like I don't need any paperwork after all. The banker just needed to fax over a copy of my DMV ID. In seven to ten business days, the change will supposedly be complete in their records.

Discover replied, telling me to either fax my documents over or send them via post. Um. No. I replied thusly:

I can't send the documents via post, I still need them; unless you're fine with a copy instead of the original. As for the fax, I don't have a fax machine.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

minestats enhancements

Day 00822: Tuesday, 2017 June 06

Unsponsored advertisements

Marc With a C is releasing a new album, Half Serious, Half Kidding EP! It's currently on pre-order, but you can listen to the first song now.

General news

Someone came onto #Minetest advertising a PHP-development gig, then left. I inquired, but it turns out the job is to write proprietary code based on the permissively-licensed Laravel. So why were they advertising in a free software channel!? I laughed and said #Minetest might not be the best place to find someone, and that most of the peopel with skills there are free software geeks. As it turns out though, the person advertising is a Minetest developer themself! They're not one of the core developers, but they're a contributor; they knew exactly what the channel is. That was a little embarrassing on my part. I'm glad I wasn't rude about it.

The on-site manager's parent brought me to the laundry room again to look at bread that someone left. It was a sweet gesture, but I still don't know if it's safe to eat. Apparently, they know the person that left it, but without an ingredient list, I could very well give myself a headache if I ate it.

minestats development hit a bit of a wall today. First, I ran into the nodes that drop default:dirt. I was a little disappointed that those nodes made it onto the stats page, but it was tolerable. It takes time for grass, snow, or whatever to spread on dirt, so players still can't place and dig back up the same node in quick succession to raise their stats. If they want to uselessly farm default:dirt_with_grass, they can feel free. farming:soil can be farmed a bit quicker, but it's still more than just placing and digging that they'd have to do. But then I noticed default:dirt_with_grass_footsteps, a node that was sort of dummied out, but never actually removed from the game. It can never be found, so it can never be mined, resulting in a stat that just sits there taunting players. Joy. I wasn't sure how to get around that, but as it's a flaw in Minetest game, not in minestats, I was willing to simply point out the problem to users of my mod, then otherwise leave it alone for the time being.

But then, a bigger problem arose. Some nodes should be removed from consideration because they only exist as technical implementations. I don't recall exactly which node made me throw in the towel, but for some nodes, the only obvious way to remove them from the consideration pool is to check for the presence of an on_place() method. Nodes such as grass define this to allow all five lengths of grass to be one item type in inventory, but five lengths in the field. When you place one, a random one of the five nodes is used. Beds use this to place the second node of the bed. Doors use this poorly to place both nodes of the door. Anyway, it turns out seeds and saplings use this too. Seeds prevent their own placement if they don't like the node beneath their now location. Saplings use this to prevent themselves from being placed in places that would allow you to commit vandalism-by-tree by growing trees into other people's protected areas. By ruling out items with an on_place() method, I rule out the main two types of non-mineral nodes I'm actually trying to count! I give up for now. I'm not up to this task.

I did get some other stuff completed successfully in that mod though. It doesn't help my personal use case, as I play mostly with the default game, but my mod now supports more minerals than before! Legacy item strings are handled with ease, as are any other unnormalised item strings. Nodes that drop several of the same item are counted as well. Nodes that can be crafted are exempt now though, preventing default:clay from being considered a minable mineral. This check was originally coded to prevent default:stone/default:cobble from being considered a mineral, but I'm happy with the clay-blocking too. I couldn't find a way to block the various forms of dirt from being counted as minables, but normally, you shouldn't be able to mine the exact same node repeatedly and get points for it.

I emailed my mother to see if tonight was a good night to visit them. I got no response, so I worked on another project.

I was going to work on minequest finally next, but instead, I was set on another mission. Someone asked me to add player kills to minestats. Obviously, that's a bad idea and I refuse to do it. It's outside the scope of what minestats is meant for. However, as a *separate* mod, it's an interesting idea. It took some time, but I coded what I think will do what the requester wanted. I don't very well have the resources to test it though, as my machine's weak and shouldn't be running multiple Minetest clients at once. I left it to the requester to test it, and said I'd be happy to fix any bugs they found.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I had a bizarre dream last night. I saw a mouse, though I quickly forgot it was there. After getting distracted by other things, I rested my hand near the mouse, about twenty centimetres away. It should've run away. That's what any other mouse would do. However, it instead ran at my hand and latched on with its long, rodent front teeth. It should've hurt quite a bit, as I do feel pain in dreams unlike some people, but I guess that's not where my brain wanted to take the dream. I expected a strong, sharp pain, but instead, the pain was rather minimal. After I got over the shock, I became more annoyed with the mouse than afraid of it, and decided to confine it while I decided what o do with it. I didn't want to kill it, but I also didn't want it roaming free in the building. The mouse was still latched onto me, but when I got up to get a marinara cup (like the ones we have at work) to put the mouse in, it released its vice grip on my hand and dropped to the floor. I manager to catch it while it was still dazed from the fall; I worried I wouldn't catch it at all though, as mice are too quick. It bit me again; though I tried to hold it in a position in which it was in no position to bite, the fact is that mice are incredibly flexible. Or at least, I assume they are, as rats are incredibly flexible, to the point where they can even shift around their bones and organs to squeeze through tight spaces. I found the marinara cup wasn't going to contain the mouse. The cup was certainly enough to hold the mouse if it held still, but as it was quickly trying to escape, I needed a larger container so I could keep the mouse away from the opening long enough to seal it in. The mouse escaped again, and once more, I quickly caught it before it could further act. At this point, I gave up trying to avoid the mouse's bite. It was like the bite of a strong garter snake; painful and, if you're not expecting it, startling. However, if you know it's coming, it's really no big deal. I found a bigger container, though I'm not sure for the life of me what. I guess it was some sort of resealable plastic wrapping from something, though the top flap had somehow shrunk, so it wasn't fitting over the harder, plastic bottom any more. I barely got the mouse to stay in that, but I kept thinking it had escaped, due to how poorly the container was even closed. Somehow though, a second mouse had gotten in. I be later, the container was more of a large tent with large windows in the side. I'm not sure how that happened, but at this point, there were three mice in it. At first, I thought they might be breeding. It was still a mystery as to where the second mouse had come from, but the third could be a product of the other two. I quickly realised though that the third mouse was as large as the other two; tiny, but not a baby. Furthermore, the mice had no food in there to build a baby out of. (Now that I'm awake, I realise one of the mice could've been pregnant before being confined, so lack of materials to build a baby from wasn't an issue, though the size of the third mouse still was.)

I'm not sure where this dream took place, really. It didn't feel like my home, but it also didn't seem like a workplace. I was alone, and with apparently no other task to accomplish besides confining a mouse on a whim.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

lapis and gems

Day 00824: Thursday, 2017 June 08

General news

I copied my documents, then mailed them to Discover. Now I just need to wait and see if they'll keep their word and honour the copies.

Yesterday, when I was trying out mineral-defining mods, I ran into two cases of mod name collision. Two mods of the same name cannot be installed simultaneously for a few reasons, the main one probably being that each mod gets its own name space to define in-game objects with, and that name space is based on the mod's name. The first collision was with the name gems. With such an unoriginal name, how could there *not* be a collision? One adds gems to make tools from. The other adds gems to encrust existing tools with, changing their properties. The second collision was with a pair of mods called lapis. This collision should have never happened. The author of the second mod knew about the first mod, even reusing code from the original. You'd think that they share some node/item names because the second is basically a continuation of the first, but you'd be wrong. They both define lapis lazuli minerals, but they don't share an internal identifier and they behave completely differently. The second mod also adds pyrite alongside lapis lazuli. Nothing about the two mods is the same, so they should use different names so they can be installed together if desired. Yesterday, I hatched a plan to merge both pairs to form new mods that take the place of their components, filling both roles, eliminating conflict, and still covering the needs of any mod that depends on either of the component parts.

Merging the gems mods might be tricky to pull off in a clean way. I'll need to extend the functionality to include more, potentially allowing all gems defined by the mod to fill either role and defining a bunch of new tools to pull it off. I thought the lapis mods would be easier though. minestats wasn't detecting the lapis lazuli ores from the second mod, so I looked into the code. It turns out the "mineral" node is craftable. It sometimes drops its gem, but usually drops a cobble version of itself, which can be smelted back into its original form. However, I thought I read that it could also be crafted into and from nine of its gems. In other words, the gem drop is "bad", as you get less of the material! That was an ugly mess and I didn't like it. I figured when I merged the mods, I'd alias the new drop to the old drop, remove the spawning of the new mineral nodes, make the new mineral nodes stop dropping the gems (so they always drop the cobble version of themselves), and make the new nodes craftable from the old gems. Nine of the old gem in a square would make the old block. Four would make the new block/mineral hybrid. This would also help deal with the new-found rarity on the new mod's end, as it was supposed to spawn full nodes instead of just minerals, so it shouldn't take a full nine gems to craft them.

As I was merging the code today though, I found I'd misread yesterday. The new mineral node isn't craftable from gems, it's only craftable by smelting its cobble form. No material is lost. So should I get minestats to count the times it drops the gem instead of the cobble? As I debated back and forth, I came up with a way to provide support for this mineral. I could check to see if any of the recipes used to craft the node require the exact drop of the node. Additionally though, I wondered if I even needed to check to see if the node is craftable at all. If I remove that check, the problem is that clay will be counted as a mineral. The same clay can be dug and placed repeatedly, boosting your clay count. This could be done intentionally, but it could also be done unintentionally when you change your mind about where you wanted the clay placed. I was torn, unsure whether this strangely-defined lapis lazuli node was deserving of inclusion as a mineral. One of my main thoughts was that with minerals, you can't choose where they are. You can't have them in your inventory, so you can't place them to dig them. That firmly rules this newer lapis lazuli out as a mineral, right? However, after a bit, I realised the inconsistency in that thought. I've been treating flint as a mineral when it falls from gravel, but gravel usually drops itself. That means the mineral node *can* exist in-inventory and the player *can* chose where to place it. This new lapis lazuli is as much a mineral as flint, so because I adamantly hold to the claim that flint counts as a mineral, I *must* provide support for this lapis lazuli if feasible, and it's plenty feasible.

After writing code to weed out empty stacks in drop sets, I realised that empty stacks were already weeded out in a better way elsewhere in my code. I'd already accounted for them. After writing up code to sort drop sets so they could be more-easily compared to craft recipes (I'd use that same function to normalise the recipes), I realised I didn't need to do that either, and undid all my code work for the day up to that point. I don't need the drops sorted. If the node drops multiple item stacks, it's already eliminated as not a mineral. If we know it only drops one item stack, what's to sort?

Having fixed the bug in minestats and having failed to make any progress whatsoever on the mod merge I thought I knew how to complete, I biked around town for a while, exercising, getting some sun, and thinking about both mod mergers. On the lapis mod, I came to a new conclusion as to how to complete it. For the most part, the mods will remain unchanged, aside from the fact that the two will now be one. However, the new lapis mod adds a couple elements. First, it adds pyrite. Second, it replaces lapis lazuli ore with blocks of lapis lazuli that are filled with calcite. At first, I tried to figure out how to change the names of these new lapis lazuli nodes to include the fact that they've got calcite, aside from the main ore node, which already has that information. However, I settled on a better plan. Instead, I'll label the old lapis lazuli minerals as *pure*. It'll get the same point across, and will allow the two to be separated. When I have time, it shouldn't take to long to get it right this time. As for the gems mod merger, I'm still lost. One one just defines minerals to be made into tools. It's pretty straightforward. The other encrusts three sets of tools. One set is the steel tools from default. The other two are the gold and mithral tools from moreores. Mese tools are mentioned as being unencrustable, but no other tools are mentioned. I imagine at the point this mod was abandoned, Minetest Game still only had wooden, stone, steel, and mese tools. It might not have even had the full mese set yet. At this point though, Minetest Game's default has bled moreores all but dry. Only two minerals are left in moreores: silver and mithral. Golden tools no longer exist. I think the obvious thing to do is extend support to all default and moreores tools, including mese, and just forget about golden tools. I can then bump up the bonuses for the encrusting gems, and make the tool gems have lower-level encrusting bonuses. I can add low-level tools that can be made from the encrusting gems as well. That way, the gems can be used for either purpose, but they work best for their respective, original purposes. I'll need to create textures for the blocks crafted from the encrusting gems, as the tools gems allow themselves to be crafted into nodes and the encrusting gems don't yet, and I'll need to do something with the fact that the tools gems define a way to make tool handles out of stone, but all that will be mostly reasonable to accomplish. The problem though, will be the diamonds in the encrusting gems mod. This mod's old and, as I said before, seems to predate the most recent tool sets. It defines diamonds because diamonds didn't yet exist. Defining diamonds in the new version of this mod could be a mess if I don't do it right, but removing them would in part defeat the purpose of this merger. I *must* include them.

One possibility I'm thinking about is to define them as low-grade diamonds or something. Perhaps they're not fit for their original purpose, and the diamonds in default will fill that role. Or perhaps, they make tools that are half the strength of regular diamond tools and have half the encrusting bonus of the regular diamonds. Or maybe, you craft together several low-grade diamonds to get a usable diamond.

My new Oregon Community Credit Union credit card arrived today. I stopped using my old one when I found I could choose a name on my Discover card, but Discover revoked that feature and I now have the legal name I want anyway. I might actually use this new card. The utility bill also arrived, but by the time I checked the mail, the utility company's office was closed. Maybe I'll pay the bill tomorrow when I get home from this food-getting thing.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I don't remember most of this dream, but the last part is still vivid in my mind. Vanessa, our mother, and I were in my mother's car, off in the wilderness, on a thin, dirt road on a slope by the waster. I had a newspaper that I was using to keep track of the events of the day with. Somehow, what I was going to write in my journal related to the content of the newspaper. However, Vanessa wanted to take my newspaper for something; I don't recall what. I scoured the newspaper to find the parts I needed, and took notes on my laptop so I wouldn't need the paper any more before giving it up. I found an article about Trump; I don't recall the specifics of what it said, but the article included a life-size balloon of Trump, uninflated and folded into the newspaper. I jokingly asked our mother if they wanted the balloon. I didn't mean any harm by it, but ...

My mother asked how it was in my apartment, no longer having to share a kitchen with someone of such drastically-different political views, referring to themself. I said I didn't mind sharing a kitchen, it didn't affect the quality of the food. That's when my mother got mean. They said it did, that when someone with a warm heart makes the food, you can taste the care they put into it. In other words, they were saying that I must have a cold heart, as I voted against Trump. At that point, I retaliated. Somehow, my mother appeared outside the vehicle though, so they didn't hear me. At that point, the road had a large dip in it, and without a driver, it nearly fell off the road. Once the car had come to a stop, I got out and repeated myself: "If you had a warm heart, you'd have voted for anyone but the republican.", adding onto the end, "If you didn't like the democrat, you could've even written in a candidate.".

Somehow, the story of the dream got rewritten at that point. My mother was holding their cat, and had been frustrated for a while, not sure how to handle moving the cat in their upcoming move. In exasperation from my words, they simply gave up, and released the cat by the road. They made sudden, startling motions to scare the already-nervous cat (the cat fears unknown environments) down the slope and to the lake, where two black cats already were. The cat would never survive there though. It doesn't know how to hunt or avoid predators. In releasing the cat, my mother sort of proved my point. I cried a bit, knowing I'd unintentionally played a hand in the cat's soon-to-be, untimely demise. I briefly considered the fact that I might, myself, be stranded too; that my mother wouldn't bring me back home from our outing. That was about when I woke up.

The ironic thing about the kitchen remark from my mother, and something I didn't even consider until I was awake, is that my mother doesn't pour love and care into meals. Additionally, when I was living there, I couldn't keep edible food around, or my mother would complain. I practically lived off of whatever I could buy and eat quickly. No large bags of potatoes, no vegetables that had to be stored in the refrigerator ... even canned goods were too much, as they were a pain to eat while out and I felt like I couldn't bring food home. I was eating mostly junk food such as potato chips. In the dream, I didn't mind sharing a kitchen with my mother. In the real world, I do.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I give up.

Day 00825: Friday, 2017 June 09

General news

The food place gave me a lot more groceries than I was expecting. I kind of wish I hadn't bought a big bag of carrots recently. They asked me for my Social Security number though, which I didn't bring with me, but they were fine without it. This soup they gave me doesn't taste good at all, but even if it represents most of what they gave me (and it probably doesn't), that'll save me a pretty penny. It can help me save up to pay off my student loans and reach a better place in life.

There are a bunch of inconsistencies in the gems mod that has gems that can be crafted into tools. I started looking at just how much the stone handles improve the tools crafted from them, and found no rhyme or reason to it. For some tools, increases were bigger, while in some, they were smaller. I ironed out the wrinkles by setting the changes to be the same for each gem's tools, though the changes are still different across tool types. Also, it seems that while the stone handles increase the tool's durability, they decrease the tool's speed. Interesting; it's a trade-off.

Looking through the code more, I found something strange; a fabricator used to cut gems. The gems from this mod are unusable until cut. What do I do with this!? Do I remove that feature, or do I expand it to encompass the rest of the gems from the other gems mod? Furthermore, the code for the fabricator is extremely broken. It borrows most of its code from the default furnace, but removes the part that consumes fuel. A diamond blade can then be crafted, which acts as the fuel, but never gets consumed because of the strange code. It was intended by the original programmer that the blade not get used up, but because of the way the code is set up, you don't need the blade at all. Any furnace fuel will activate the fabricator and it won't be consumed. Additionally, if you put the blade in a regular furnace, it'll be consumed rather quickly. Finally, raw gems can be put in a regular furnace and cooked into their cut counterparts. Ugh, what a mess ... It'd be easy to fix, too, if I didn't want to keep the crafting chain intact. minequest needs an intact crafting chain in order to find nodes made from a given mineral. Without that, I'd have no reservations simply removing the gem-cooking recipes and using a custom handler. Reservations or no reservations, this is what I'd have to do to make my combined mod presentable.

So, here's the list of concepts I need to integrate together into one mod so far:

Gems can be crafted into tools
Gems can be used to encrust tools and strengthen them
Tools can be crafted with stone handles instead of wooden ones for better durability at the cost of slower mining speeds
Raw gems aren't usable; they need to be refined first
Gems can be crafted into blocks
There's a second type of diamond that must somehow relate to or differentiate itself sufficiently from regular diamonds

The mods contradict each other a bit too. One expects diamonds to exist already, and uses them to craft the fabricator. The other expects them not to exist already, and defines them itself. I think I give up. Trying to merge mods to both preserve them (they're currently unmaintained, which is why one of them even still has diamonds) and to resolve the name conflict was a nice idea in theory, but I'm not the person for the job. I'm too rigid in what I want to preserve about them, and proper preservation of most of the mod requires cutting away the part that conflicts with the current game. For now, I'll stick to just supporting the mineral mods from my mods and trying to draw attention to the mineral mods so they aren't forgotten and lost.

Having put down the code of others, I picked up my own again. I've added a few new features to minestats. First, if there are less than ten minerals defined, the last line of the stats page is no longer reserved for the page number and previous/next buttons. The ninth mineral will be moved from page one to page zero and page one will be removed. Second, if more than nine minerals are defined, the text with the name of each mineral will be removed. Stats will be shown in a condensed form to conserve pages, allowing twice as many per page to be shown. This time, if less than eighteen minerals are defined, the last line isn't reserved and can be used to display stats. Otherwise, the last line will be reserved for the page number and next/back buttons. I re-added the item names, though I kind of squished them in there with the numbers. It took some trial and error, but I got the default mineral names to look good condensed. I'll need to do some work on non-default minerals though. Specifically, some have very long names, so they'll need to be trimmed in a clean way to look decent in such a small space. It'd be a lot easier if the game used a fixed-width font. I've also added a debug command to output the names of all minerals, making it even easier to see what is included and what isn't.

At work, out head manager claimed that we're all getting a "raise". However, it's just minimum wage going up. Minimum wage going up is *not* a raise! I need to get out of there. It's really not the best environment to work in. I feel it's in my best interest to stay a while longer though. At a bare minimum, I need to establish my existence as Alex Yst. I need a work history, even if a short one, in which an employer knows my by my actual name. Then, I can look for work elsewhere. As I've probably said before, there's a high probability I'll stay until I have my associate degree anyway. With my low-level degree, I can try for better employment opportunities while I continue with my bachelor degree.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was living at my old H Street house and was playing a card game with a friend outside. I found a mysterious pack of giant cards lying out, so I opened it, but we both soon regretted it. They seemed to be some sort of trading card, though each represented some sort of demon. The first demon was summoned, and as it started to arrive, we rushed into the house to hide. We thought our only chance of getting rid of the demons might lie in the cards, but I accidentally dropped them as I rand. I started to head back, but the wind picked up. I can't remember what happened with the first and second demon, but the third was some sort of tornado demon. Its summoning was marked by a tornado, and I watched in horror as he tornado sucked up the cards and blew most of them away. I ran inside, but as I locked the door, the wind died down, so I risked unlocking the door at retrieve what was left of the cards. At that moment though, the tornado demon itself showed up, so I couldn't get any of the cards. I tried to relock the door and hide, but it saw me and tried to get in. I barely got the door locked because the wind it exuded was pulling the door open and the sliding, glass door had been replaced with swinging, glass doors. To complicate things, these were they type of doors that swung both ways; they had to be perfectly aligned for the lock in the one door to latch into the hole in the other. Without the cards and with our hiding place exposed, I wasn't sure what we were going to do about the stream of demons that was pouring in.

I had another dream where I was in a bed dragged by police dogs, got yanked out of the bed by a dog once we got to the criminal, then flew around messing with people verbally. When I was being dragged, one of the dogs ran at me, and I thought it was going to attack me. It actually wasn't interested in me, and just jumped up onto the bed to jump off past the bed. Everyone seemed oblivious to my presence whenever I was in the air though, so my messing with them was ineffective. A flock of several types of baby birds on the ground thought I was their mother, and I tried feeding them almond milk. One of them ate a magnet that fell off my person, but none were interested in the almond milk.

University life

My name still hasn't been fixed in the classroom, so I contacted my program advisor again. I really hope to have this resolved before the coming term starts. I'd like to interact with my fellow students under my real name.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

So many ideas, so little time to implement them

Day 00826: Saturday, 2017 June 10

General news

My mother and I planned to meet up today and tomorrow, but it looks like they changed their plans on me. No worries though, I woke up too early and am kind of tired, anyway.

I considered adding support in minequest for nodes that drop absolutely nothing. There are strange chests in glooptest that are spawned during mapgen, but when harvested, drop nothing. Being able to see how many of these chests you'd found would be nice. However, when I coded up the beginnings of support for this kind of stat tracking, I saw the only things tracked in Minetest Game were both kinds of fire and all bad crops. So ... while miners get their success tracked, the main thing tracked for above-ground players would be their farming failures. As for fire, putting out permanent flames is no accomplishment. I suppose acting as a firefighter and putting out the other type of fire could be positive, but it'd be better to just not start those kinds of fires. Anyway, this doesn't bode well for arbitrary-drop-list-length support. Now, in addition to having a complete inability to reliably display such drops on the stats page, I need to deal with the fact that zero-item drops are usually not a positive thing to track. My new, compact design doesn't fit well with arbitrarily-long lists of items, either. Worry for space was already a concern before I crunched everything together.

While messing around between coding things, I found an item-duplication bug. If you dig the node under a grass node, two grass items fall instead of one. I thought it was a bug in Minetest. The only mods I had running was minestats and a mod I put random debugging code in, neither of which should introduce that sort of thing. I disabled them both to be sure though. I was wrong! minestats was doing it! Ugh. It seems that when the node supporting an attached node, such as grass or a torch, is removed, the minetest.get_node_drops() function is called on the attached node. However, there's no digger, so minetest.handle_node_drops() is never called. In minetest.get_node_drops(), I set an extra key containing the dug node's name to be used by minetest.handle_node_drops(), then minetest.handle_node_drops() removes it. This allows me to get ahold of the node name, the drops, and the player object all at once, as there's no callbacks that actually allow me to have all this information at once. I found a way to pull off what I need though. I added a space and a zero to the end of the node name when adding it to the drops. That way, Minetest will interpret it as an empty stack while my code can simply ignore the quantity.

I had a flash of inspiration as to how to add some surface elements to minestats in an otherwise vanilla instance of Minetest Game. What if dropped nodes are irrelevant? What if a counted mineral can be acquired even if the node drops it along with other nodes? This has two implications. First, it would allow farm crops to be countable when they drop their crop as opposed to their seed, even if they drop the seed also. Second, as the drop counted isn't the full drop of the node, it begs the question of if the dug node is even relevant. Should I merge the counts of dropped items dropped by different nodes? Should I count a drop of three of the same item as the same as three drops of one of that same item? Logic tells me yes. My passion tells me no. I like having the node display by the drop in the menu. If the node is unknown or if multiple nodes have that same drop, I can't have that any more. Even more so, I don't like the idea that when a node drops a variable number of something, the numbers should simply be added together. I like knowing not only how many of the item I've collected, but also home many of the node I've dug and at what frequency I get each number of drops. But is keeping that separated out inconsistent with counting only part of the drop to begin with? I'm not sure. I programmed the beginnings of support for the itemised version of this, and it spammed the stats page with various cotton and wheat plant stages. Two plants, multiplied by eight stages, multiplied by two drop levels (one or two of the crop). That's thirty-two of what is basically only two plants. It seems quite a bit excessive, and yet, each one of those nodes is important for game play to farmers. In other words, the problem is in my mod, not farming. In the case of farming, I don't mind merging the drops. Farm plants are renewable, which means what I care about is the total number acquired, not where they came from. On the other hand, minerals are *not* renewable, so I care about drop rates. If there's only so much of the material, I want to know exactly how much I'm getting gypped! Furthermore, if I merge the drops and ignore what node they come from, there are only two farming drops and eight mineral drops in Minetest Game. Honestly, minestats is still skewed in favour of miners.

I ran out of time to program, but I did a lot of thinking about minestats today. I came to a realisation: it's no wonder I've been failing to find a way to capture surface nodes to log. There are three main sets of nodes. There are the nodes underground. These nodes are often finite in quantity, but with how large the underground is, there's plenty of them. Then, there's the renewable surface nodes. These nodes can be created in mass, but it takes time. Rarest of all, we have the finite surface nodes. Most people think these are the most common nodes, but they're only on the surface and the surface is so thin. For the most part, these nodes just get moved around, not used up, though you could waste desert stone to make stone picks or something. Anyway, this second type of node, the renewable surface nodes, typically take the form of plants. A key part of their renewability though is the fact that they leave behind something that can be placed in the world, something that will change into several nodes, which will once again leave behind something so the cycle can continue. I've been ruling out nodes that drop more nodes. Anti-node-dropping is anti-renewal though! I don't need to detect against node-dropping or multi-item-dropping, I just need to detect in favour of craft-item-dropping. It's worth noting though that while this allows me to log farm plants, it puts the logging of saplings and seeds so far out of reach that it's not even worth continuing to attempt to log them at all. Farm plants will have to be enough.

I started in my mind reevaluating the way I classified nodes for consideration. When I use the term "mineral" in Minetest, I'm not referring to metals and stones. I'm referring to nodes that drop a single craft item instead of themselves. I just call them minerals because most of them represent things you'd actually call minerals in the real world. I came up with two new terms to describe the phenomenons I was now trying to measure. First are the hybrid minerals. These drop not only the craft item that a true mineral would drop, but also a node. The craft item should be logged and the node ignored. Second, we have the compound minerals. These minerals drop multiple craft items. Each can be logged separately, though we don't have a good way to measure them as a single drop just yet. Later in the day, I realised that compound minerals were just a subclass of hybrid minerals, just mixed with other minerals and not a regular node.

I've been planning to put plants on a separate page if I could figure out how to log them for as long as I've been trying to include plants at all. Additionally, as I'll have to leave the node data out for the plants, they won't fit the format for the minerals page. The only way to include them is to either leave off the nodes for all logged items or put the plants elsewhere. It's far too cool having the mineral nodes display, so I'm not removing that feature. At this point, my main motivation for continuing to try to log plant-harvesting has been to try to balance the mod and make it less biased against surface-dwellers. I'm a complete mole, but not everyone is. Now that I'm so close, I started thinking about what I'm going to do about the separate menu pages. If I make the starting page, before switching, be the mineral page, it makes the plants seem less important. I don't want to make the plants seem like second-class harvestables though. If I do the reverse, I make the minerals seem less important. What to I do for fair treatment? I found a solution though. When choosing the stats tab, the page automatically chosen to start at will be determined by the player's elevation. When underground, the mineral page will be the default. When near or above the surface, plants will take precedence. Additionally, I thought about the inclusion of node data for minerals but not plants. Is that fair? Game-play-wise, it makes sense. The default game defines eight different plant nodes for each of the two crops. Logging all that separately will result in a stats page people won't enjoy because it looks far too itemised and redundant. However, can we justify this in a way that isn't specific to Minetest Game; a way that is subgame-agnostic? It turns out we can! The mineral nodes only drop one thing, so we can see a direct conversion from one state to another. However, with the plants, part of the plant becomes the crop and another becomes the seed. We can't see which part becomes which, so we can't separate it out. We can't show a before state, as we don't know the before state of the pure item, not entangle with the other item. We don't have to keep them itemised either, as the pure before state of each is probably the same, but the node is different because the crop is mixed with something else, so it looks different. In the case of plants, it's mixed with a different stage of the organism. I think I've found the true purpose of minestats: to log the dropping of non-nodes when digging nodes. With this more clear goal in mind, I think I'll end up with better results than I've been getting.

With the problems of minestats seemingly solved, I turned my attention to minequest. Now, I had four plants to choose from in addition to the eight minerals. Do I make minequest default to use plants for some bonus slots? That seems like a good idea. But which minerals do I remove from the default line-up? Or do I have more than eight bonus slots? Do I have two slots for each plant, as each plant can drop either one or two of its crop, so there are two stats for each? While it would balance out the bonus slots by having half be for surface nodes and half for subterranean nodes, I decided against this plan. It might've worked for the original design of minequest, but in its current, more dynamic state, it would result in two slots with the same available bonuses. That's needlessly boring. Should I randomise the default slots, using all available minerals and mineral hybrids, based on the world seed? At first, I liked this idea. It seemed to remove the hard-coded connection between minequest and Minetest Game, but that was only a ruse. minequest has to add the default bonuses for the items from Minetest Game, so it's already got to be hard-coded to know about minerals from it. The default bonus slots should therefore actually be thought out. I decided the likely minerals to leave out will be flint and gold. Just like having multiple bonus slots that take the same bonus-giving items would be boring, flint and gold have the least amount of bonus options, so they're the least fun.

I thought about the bonus items wheat and cotton would have at their disposal. Wheat is kind of limited, but it's got a few option. Cotton though, can be crafted into a multitude of coloured wools (as wool comes from cotton in Minetest, not animals). Each colour would do something different. After a bit though, I realised that cotton would only have access to the white wool node. The other colours of wool are crafted using group-based craft recipes. minequest ignores those. Originally, this was a bug, but it became a feature later. I left out group compatibility in the craft-chain-detection because I didn't like the idea that a bonus item might be crafted without the mineral that powers its bonus. For example, a vessel shelf is crafted from six wood and three vessels, vessels being items in the vessel group. Vessels can be made from steel, but they can also be instead made from glass. If the shelf is made without steel, why should it work with the iron bonus slot? Since it's not possible to tell which items were made with or without iron, only those that *could have been*, the way to play it safe would be to disable this group-based detection. But now, giving options for surface-dwellers seemed to depend on adding group support. I thought about it more, and came to a conclusion I'd missed before. Group-based recipes are dynamic, but the logic behind ignoring them doesn't make sense. Someone could define two recipes for crafting a single item; one that includes a mineral and one that doesn't. Unless I'm going to rule out those items too, it makes no sense to ignore group-based crafting. Like with the lapis mod and gravel treatment, consistency dictates that I must add this feature.

I'll probably have almost no time to code any of this tomorrow, but maybe I'll get a chunk of it done the next day.

The purple-veined dandelions I got at the food giveaway yesterday looked like they wouldn't keep too long, so I sliced them up to use in soup. What's the proper way to prepare dandelion? I have no idea, and I didn't look it up; I just boild them with everything else. I also sliced up the rest of my green onions, as they looked like they would be spoiled beyond th epoint of usability soon. I'd originally planned to use the kale for the soup instead of dandelions, but the kale looks like it has quite a bit of shelf life. I have so many carrots right now, so I chopped some up and threw them in too. Most of them are carrots I bought myself, and after visiting the food place, I kind of with I'd waited for carrots. I threw in nutritional yeast, bullion, soy milk, water, rice, and fake meat ... I hoped it'd come out well. It didn't. This soup is outright nasty. It's only the dandelions themselves that are so horrid though; the rest of the soup's perfectly fine. I'm convinced that either I don't like dandelions (I can't remember ever eating them before) or I've prepared them completely wrong. In any case, I don't plan to get dandelions again any time soon. After work, I added almost a full bottle of oregano, some fake cheese that I'd planned to use for sandwiches, more nutritional yeast, and some lemon dill seasoning, all in hopes of making this soup more tolerable by drowning out the dandelions. I refused to just throw the soup away; I'm going to eat it no matter what it takes to get it down. I'm kind of sad to lose that fake cheese though, I almost never buy that stuff, and can't really afford to buy more now. Thankfully, I was able to make the soup decent. The dandelions are no longer so terrible, so ... bitter, I guess would be the best way I can describe them. I think the oregano was the most likely to be the key. I'm not a big user of spices usually though, so if I need to keep a pantry full of oregano to make dandelions edible, I shouldn't keep dandelions in my refrigerator.

I may or may not have mentioned it, but I got ahold of a bed frame a while back. It's one of those small, collapsible, metal frames with the wheels. I think it's only twin-sized though, and without the bed slats, the thing's useless for now. I've repeatedly stepped on it over the past month or so, and every time, it hurts. I try to avoid it, but sometimes I forget. Today, I managed to gouge my heel pretty good on it though. Up until today, I hadn't actually injured myself. I've left the bed frame where it's been out of lack of another place to put it, but now, I made sure to *find* a place to put it. It's not the best place, but I've stashed it, upright, in the closet with the water heater.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was sitting on my bike, with my bike locked to a bike rack. I forget what I was doing, but I wasn't planning on moving any time soon. A thief ran up with a pair of bolt cutters, asked if I minded if they stole my bike, and cut the lock. They seemed to think their presence would either scare me away or startle me off my bike so they could take it, and when it didn't, they ran off without the bike to steal other things. Instead, I was mostly shocked, so I stayed put for a few moments while I took in the scene. Looking around, there were several thieves, all part of the same group, taking anything that wasn't nailed down. I was afraid, but also defensive of my bike, and glad I didn't leave it unattended. With nothing binding the bike to the rack any more, I rode the bike away as quickly as I could, frequently checking behind me to see if I was being pursued. I wasn't. The thieves weren't interested in me, or so I thought.

I ended up with Cyrus somehow, and the bike was no longer with me. Random people seemed to want to get ahold of us, but were trying to act unsuspicious. I didn't buy it though, and we ran. The thieves nearly caught up with us, but then they made the mistake of talking to the other people that wanted us and asking about us. The apparent leader of the combined group, one of the non-"thieves", told them off for their idiocy in blowing the cover of the non-"thieves", and motioned in our direction. We'd seen the whole thing. It appeared they were part of some normally-stealthy government agency that wanted us, but this wan't explicitly stated. They managed to back us into a corner, and we had no where to run.

At this point, I came to two realisations. First, this was a dream. I could do whatever I pleased. Second, I had to protect Cyrus. I guess I didn't fully comprehend the fact that this was a dream after all, as I thought Cyrus and the danger we were in were real. I let out an energy blast from my hands, burning into disintegration half of our pursuers. I hit hat many due to their close proximity. I let out a second blast, nearly frying a small child that had come up on us, but I stopped the energy mid-air and dissipated it. This was a dream, and I could do whatever I felt like. I then let out a third energy blast and disintegrated the other half of our pursuers, again, able to hit them all because they were crowded around us. I felt a little bad about the killing (again, I only seemed to *partly* realise this was a dream), but I knew I'd done what I had to.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Half Serious, Half Kidding EP

Day 00828: Monday, 2017 June 12

Unsponsored advertisements

Marc With a C has released their Half Serious, Half Kidding EP! I'm anxious to hear what's on it, but it's late and I need to get to bed.

General news

I've added node images for farm crops in minestats! These images aren't entirely accurate due to the combined nature of the stat, but they make the farming stats page match the mining stats page.

I really wanted to spend some time outside, so I rode around town much of the pre-work day. I picked up some soy milk too. The checker at the Dollar Tree said a while back that they don't recall soy milk ever being stocked there, but I swear, it seems to come in fairly often. It's not always there when I look for it, but it's there often enough.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was trying to figure out a bug, a strange and inconvenient loop in a game. My mother's cat was living with me, and suddenly, I heard a hiss. A huge spider with a leg span wider than my face ha descended most of the way down from the ceiling and was near the cat. Its body and legs were thin and a pale yellow. I was thinking about how best to get the thing outside without getting bitten, when it suddenly propelled itself at my face somehow. I was quite confused as to how it did this, as it was dangling (from a web strand) in mid air at the time and had nothing to push off against to jump. I blocked it with my hand, and the thing latched on with its legs pretty well. I was afraid of it, so I used my other hand to detach the legs from my first hand, then threw the spider into the next room (not the one the cat was in). It stayed put for about a second, flipping itself right side up, then launched itself at me again, this time using its long legs to push off against the floor.

Ugh. I hate spiders. I just want them to stay out of my home and away from me. Normally they at least don't target me and attack though.

University life

My name has now been fixed in the classroom! I'm now free to interact with my professors and fellow students in the coming term under my real name.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My last day off before school starts

Day 00829: Tuesday, 2017 June 13

General news

I biked to the Dollar Tree to buy the last of their soy milk. I need to stock up while I can, as they don't always have it.

I sat down to program group-based recipe support for minequest. At first, things did not go well. At all. First, every group-based recipe seemed to accept every item into a given mineral crafting tree, regardless of if they belonged to the group or groups in question. Then, no group-based crafting recipes seemed to bring anything into the crafting trees ever. Once I finally got it working correctly though, I got some surprising, yet completely correct, results. Coal lumps can be crafted into black dye. Black dye can be crafted with any colour of wool to make black wool. Black wool can be crafted with any colour of dye to make that colour of wool. Simply put, this means that any colour of wool can have a little coal in it, so coal can power any wool-based bonus. Strange, right? I think I'll keep that feature secret and see if anyone finds it and brings it up. Additionally, dye can be mixed to form other colours of dye. By bringing black dye into the list of mineral items, coal lumps brought all dye colours into the fold. I think coal might be the only mineral of the default ten (including wheat and cotton, which aren't logically minerals) to provide support for dye. It's not something that jumps straight to mind when I think of crafts involving coal, but it should make things more interesting. Again, I'll keep this to myself until someone mentions it. It'll be a little Easter egg.

I've got new, more flexible plans for minequest. Instead of third-party mods determining which eight minerals players will be able to get bonuses from, each player will decide that for themself. That'll allow all mineral stats to potentially have use, and allow players to get benefit from which minerals they most enjoy harvesting. Miners will use the eight actual minerals, most likely. Farmers will more-likely replace two to four of those with farm crops. By design though, choosing your minerals will be a bit of a commitment. Changing bonus items without changing minerals only requires disabling the bonus you want to switch out, then enabling the new bonus. However, switching even one of your minerals will require disabling *all* your bonuses. You can of course re-enable them after you switch, but if any of your bonuses were storing data, that data will be lost. For example, the steel door's bonus will likely be the ability to set up to a set number of warp points at places you've been on the map. This number will be determined by the amount of iron you've mined. When you disable that bonus though, all your warp points are deleted. If you turn that bonus back on later and want those warp points back, you'll have to go back and visit those places on foot and re-bookmark them! Other bonuses have less severe consequences for temporarily disabling them though. For example, the powered rail probably will boost your walking speed. Disabling it would set you back to your normal speed, but you get your speed boost back right away when you re-enable it. The new, more-dynamic setup of minequest will probably require a complete rewrite of everything I've coded for it before getting minestats pretty much in order. That'll be a pain, but I think it'll be worth it for the results.

I didn't get anywhere close to finishing the configuration interface, which must be completed before I can move on to anything else (otherwise, I won't be able to test the features as I program them, as they depend on the configuration), but I feel like I got a lot done. It doesn't look like much, but I learned to use the item stack meta data API enough to get the beginnings of the interface to self-organise when players move everything around, and I corrected the item-cloning issue that arose from not knowing which items were pulled from the options already if a player switches out of the configuration menu before saving. I also coded a callback to prevent item stacks in the configuration interface from being split if they contain multiple items or combined ever. None of the items in this interface are usable by the player, they're just an abstraction to make configuration easy and intuitive. Unexpected stacks caused by splitting and merging only serve to cause trouble and make the interface seem broken. If I chisel away at this a little more, I should have the configuration page in working order. It was time to put down the code though and take a break. I headed to a local park on my bicycle to unwind.

Island Park quickly became boring, so I left and wandered the town on my bike instead. As usual, I let my mind wander. At first, I just thought about how far I'd managed to progress with minequest. The true purpose of minestats is to act as a base for minequest to build off of, and that alone was quite a chunk of code to write. minequest proper is coming together now as well. After a bit though, I started actually thinking about what I need to work on next in the code. The obvious next step was to experiment with and learn to use Minetest inventory loops. Though still unusable, minequest has evolved past its limited ability to make use of only eight, hard-coded minerals. Now, it supports more than just minerals, and certainly up to more than eight. However, despite its more dynamic nature, it's still limited to forty countable items, due to the inventory size of the configuration screen and the fact that eight slots are reserved for dumping unwanted, previously-used countable items. If I could get an inventory loop going, I could set an arbitrary inventory size, exactly the size needed, and it'd all be accessible. However, I came to the realisation that that plan would kill my ability to reserve those eight slots on each page. I could set aside a separate inventory that *looks* like a part of the first, but if inventory loops work anything like the way I think they do (that is, they work client-side), I wouldn't be able to clear the empty slots when the page is turned. I could clear them as soon as they were used, but I might as well set up an ugly trash slot if I was going to do that. It's not what I'm after. I know exactly how to achieve the effect I'm after without an inventory loop, but I was going to try an inventory loop anyway because I thought it was the right way to do it. Now that I know it's not, I can focus on doing it the way that'll actually work. I'll still need to learn how to use inventory loops later though, as they'll no doubt be useful for the locked chest bonus.

Next, I started thinking about the main hub towns of the server I want to one day host. I have nine towns, and eight minerals. But now ... I've made farm plants countable. Should I not represent them with towns? That brings the total town themes to ten though, while there are still only nine hub towns, and it's going to stay that way. My first thought was to combine the farm plant towns. This combined-theme town could still dawn the centre town's original planned name, World's Navel. Not only is it at the centre of the world, but also, its theme would be generation, mostly in the form of farm crops. That wouldn't be paying due respect to the farming aspect of the game though. It's true that I love mining and I'm not really a fan of farming. However, this isn't my personal, private world, and I shouldn't be pushing one aspect any more than any other, save for the aspects I'm adding myself in the form of minequest. Than means I'll need to leave out a mineral. But which one? Again, I thought to leave out one of the farm plants, but again, that answer was clearly dead wrong. Even including both farm plants, the farm towns will still be outnumbered by the mining towns. There's nothing I can do about that, but I shouldn't make it worse. After a while though, it dawned on me: I should leave out flint! You can't actually build anything out of flint. The town of Flint; the only one of the nine towns to be named directly after a mineral instead of having a name composed of a mineral and something to make it sound like a town, such as Tin Town and Mesetropolis; was already planned to be a total sham. It was going to mirror Coal City, using mostly coal-themed node, but with them set on fire. Eliminating Flint removes this anomaly. Besides, flint is a stupid mineral. It's only use seems to be to consume the greatest mineral, iron.

Now, I had the job of figuring out which town should be in the centre. Whatever town ended up in the centre would become the permanent spawn town eventually, if all went well. The obvious choice was one of the farm towns. A nice town that promoted sustainability would be an excellent choice. However, there was a catch. I want similar towns to be across the map from one another. I'd already put the minerals in pairs. Tin and copper were paired, as their main purpose in-game is to be combined into bronze. Gold and iron go together, as all ownable nodes have some iron in them and gold's primary function is to craft keys with which to share what you own. Diamond and mese form a pair because they're the hardest minerals of the game. In their ore form, they're the only two ores incapable of being mined with a renewable pick. Flint and coal form a pair as both are needed to form the permanent flame node. The two farm crops would obviously form a pair as well. The odd one out now seemed to be coal, as its mate had been dropped. But do I want Coal City to be the main town for ever? No, that would be terrible! It could be interpreted as just a game, which would be fine, but it could also be interpreted as being in favour of fossil fuels. I never burn coal in-game because it's a finite resource, but that's not what it would look like. But what else could coal pair with? Tin and bronze are inseparable as a pair. Pairing either with something else would look stupid. The farm crops are likewise a pair not to be split up. That leaves gold/iron and diamond/mese. I'd love to put the iron town in the centre, but coal doesn't seem like it pairs with gold well. Besides, I like iron the best, but that doesn't mean everyone does. Could I justify making the main town's theme be iron? Probably not. But then it hit me. Coal and diamond are both made of carbon in the real world, while mese isn't even real. Coal and diamond can form a pair, leaving mese, a substance unique to Minetest, as the theme of the centre town. It would look like the main town was sort of a tribute to the game. Perfect! There shouldn't be anything objectionable about that at all.

Now that I'm home, I came up with a couple other ideas. First, I could've combined the copper-themed city and the tin-themed city to form a single copper-, tin-, and bronze-themed town. I'm not doing that though, as I'd much rather remove flint from the lineup if I've got a valid excuse to do so. And I do. Second, minestats (and therefore minequest) treats wheat and cotton each as two minables; one that drops one of the crop and one that drops two. Should there be a second cotton-themed city and a second wheat-themed city? Maybe. They wouldn't be one of the main nine though. And if I start expanding after the main nine are in place, should flint finally get a city too? Should clay, which minestats deliberately doesn't count, also get a city eventually because it still drops craft items? I don't know. That'll be a long way off though, if it ever even comes to that. It'll take several years to get the tunnels between the main nine cities set up, and after that, I might just start something else instead of continuing the tunnel project. That several-year estimate also ignores the fact that last time, people asked me to provide tunnels to their places. If that happens again this time, and continues happening, we might not even make it past the first or second hub town, let alone have time to make it to outlying towns.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I Was at a New Year's Eve party with my coworkers. I didn't realise what the party was at the time. It was getting late, so I wad about to head home, but one of my coworkers stopped me. They offered me beer, but I declined, as I don't drink. They then offered me hot dogs, which again, I don't eat, but I decided to stay because they seemed intent on having me there. They then asked me to explain my name change to them, though they thought I had changed *from* Alex Yyst to some name I'd never heard of. I explained that I had actually changed my name *to* Alex Yst, and that it was Yst, not Yyst. They still couldn't pronounce my name though. I woke up before I could answer their questions about what the name means though. They thought the name might be Canadian.

It was too early to be awake, so I went back to bed. I dreamed I arrived back home from work to find thin smoke streaming from my laptop, which was on my bed. I thought the thing had overheated and was burning the sheets. The sheets were fine though, it was coming from the computer itself. I've known I need to replace this thing soon, but with it smoking, the tame table on that just got moved up. Now that I'm awake though, I'm going to continue putting off replacing it for a while. I simply don't have extra money to spare.

Mental health watch

I have an active imagination. When I'm travelling or doing mindless work, I like to have a puzzle to work on, usually a programming problem that I'm trying to solve. When I don't have one, or even sometimes when I do, I daydream, often about magic. My magic form, as well as the magic forms of others, tend to have patterned markings on our skin. While everyone else's markings are symmetrical or almost-so, in the past, I've always imagined my markings as showing up only on my left half. My right half has been completely normal-looking, save for whatever skin and hair colours I've had at the time. Last night though, I noticed that this hasn't been the case lately. I've imagined my markings as being symmetrical as everyone else's. I kind of wonder if this is my subconscious telling me that I felt like half a person before, and that I feel more whole now.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Gotta' go into work tomorrow

Day 00830: Wednesday, 2017 June 14

General news

I spent the morning and into the afternoon walking and biking. While I was out, I thought about the barter system I'd like to get set up on my Minetest server. It'd be nice to have some sort of cash system, but how would that even work? I've come up with various options in the past, but I never like how they work. One option is to have players start out with a set amount of money when they join the server for the first time. More money can be acquired by selling goods to other players. However, this encourages users to create several accounts and pipe the money all into their main account's wallet. Another option is to give players a set amount of money every so often. However, this encourages players to create several accounts, logging into them every once in a while to transfer cash to the main account. Again, artificially encouraging the creation of multiple accounts is something I'd like to avoid. With this second plan comes another problem though: inflation. The longer you've played, the more money you'll have, even if you don't work for it. The longer the world's been in use, the less the economy is even good for anything. For this reason, the only feasible way I've been able to figure out how to get an economy running is through barter. However, while I was out, I came up with another plan. When mining certain nodes, they can have a one in one hundred (or some other probability) chance of dropping some sort of currency instead of themself. To give the currency value, it'd actually be backed; any amount of money placed in the crafting grid in any formation will result in some otherwise-finite resource being crafted. This'd fix the problem of lack of renewability in Minetest! I think many players will still use barter instead, as the cash will be better used for generating materials from. Some players are ... strange, though. For example, I knew a player that thought mese shards were great currency. They didn't like that I removed them from my world. The problem? Mese shards in Minetest at the time were completely worthless. You could break a mese crystal into nine shards, but once you did, the shards could never be crafted back into a crystal. (This problem has since been fixed, thankfully.) Furthermore, there was nothing you could craft out of mese crystal fragments; unless you had a full crystal, all you had was trash.

I'm putting minequest away for now to work on this new idea. I may or may not pick minequest back up in the future. It's a nice concept, but I think it fills a need I no longer have. My goal in the past when modding Minetest has been to use a subtle touch, affecting the state of the game world as little as possible. I no longer feel boxed in like that though. Minequest is a lot of code that boils down to just being able to customise a character, changing game play without touching the actual world much. Honestly, I think I'd like to come back to it at some point, but if and when I do, coming up with all the bonuses is going to take a while. It might never be finished. Never mind. I just realised that this mod *has to* be completed. Its completion proves the minestats API is complete enough to build off of, and in building minequest, I'll come across the holes in the API that need to be patched.

I wrote up some code to have Minetest tally up the number of possible recipes involving only my new currency. There are four hundred! There are only three hundred seventy-eight items in Minetest Game, and that doesn't even remove the items I don't want to provide recipes for, such as undug minerals, still in their node form. Clearly, the initial idea needed refinement. I decided to randomise the recipes and support as many items as possible. In an otherwise-vanilla copy of Minetest Game, that'd be all of them, but if mods were added, there could be more items than available recipes. Next, I needed a way to rule out items that should never be crafted. After thinking a while, I decided against the randomisation plan, and instead make two hundred items craftable, each via one of two recipes. I'd have some fallbacks for in case some Minetest Game mods weren't installed, and if too few of the mods were installed, I'd drop the item count to one hundred and provide four recipes each. default alone has over one hundred items I'd feel fine making recipes for, and I have to depend on that mod anyway to turn some of the nodes into ores to sometimes dig strange coins from.

I came up with an even better idea later though. strangecoins, my new money mod, can depend on minestats! The dependency will more than likely be soft, but if both are installed, which items you can purchase from the server will depend on your mining/farming stats. Nine strange coins can be crafted into a shop node. Each purchasable item will have a price, a mineral, and a stat requirement. Depending on which stats you increase, you'll have access to different items to buy. Unless you get *all* your default stats and all the stats added by strangecoins up to a certain level, there will be some things you just can't buy. I'll also add an API to allow the adding of more stats and more items for purchase to the shop node. While sorting purchasable items into what mineral/crop they'd belong to, I found that coal cannot be, even in minute traces, in yellow or white dye. Interesting.

I did my laundry early this time, getting it done when I only had one load to do instead of two. Strangely, the dryer I used gave me twelve minutes per quarter I fed it, as opposed to the usual ten. I wonder if the other dryers are doing this now too.

I was planning to stay up and start my coursework tonight; the term begins at 22:00. However, I received an email from a coworker. They need me to cover a morning shift, which means I need sleep. I'll take a look at the first week's work before I head out tomorrow so I can think about what I need to submit when I get back.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed my mother had encountered a "rock fish". No explanation was given as to what a rock fish actually was, but my mother was confused to have encountered it in the house. Apparently, they live inside crumbly rocks. I was a bit confused. They couldn't actually be a type of fish that lives on land inside these crumbly rocks, could they? Alyssa admitted they'd been crumbling a crumbly rock onto the floor for the past while, so the rock fish had probably come out of that. Our mother was annoyed by this, and told Alyssa to clean up the mess. I actually encountered the thing later. I turns out these rock fish were a type of persistent, flying, biting insect. I found it when it bit my shin, and I knocked it off. It kept flying at me, and I kept batting it away with whatever I was holding at the time; I forget what that was. The insect was mildly annoying at worst though.

It's worth noting that real rockfish live in water, *amongst* rocks, not in them.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My neighbour's birthday

Day 00834: Sunday, 2017 June 18

General news

I went to work early to get fresh bread sticks for my neighbour and return, as I feel bad about them getting those ones left at their door overnight. When I got back, my neighbour seemed to be out though. I hoped they would get back while they're still sort of fresh, but I didn't think I'd try this a third time. They probably already had more bread sticks than they want. Later, I saw them, and sure enough, they had more than they wanted. They offered me some, but I declined on account of the cheese on them. They said even the ones from last night were good though, which is a relief. I mean, I'd still eat them after a day if they didn't have cheese, but many people wouldn't.

Today was a very slow day at work.

Someone came in with a $100 USD bill, trying to spend part of it, but we have a policy against accepting bills larger than a twenty. The head manager has given me a blanket approval to accept fifties and hundreds anyway in the past, but two of the shift leaders tell me off when I do. I told them the head manager lets me, but they said there's no way that's true. They said I can take fifties, but not hundreds, and they've told me off on a few occasions for accepting hundreds, so I gave up. I've been telling every customer that tries to get me to break a hundred that we can't accept those bills, and I point to the sign saying fifties and hundreds can't be accepted. I was lucky to be dealing with this customer though. They'd called ahead and been told by someone (I assume the head manager) that we could break it. I asked the head manager about it, and they said to take it, then started showing me all the anti-counterfeit checks to perform visually. I explained that I knew those checks and always performed them, but that I get told off when I take those bills. They asked who was telling me off, and told me to tell them off. Also, they told one of the two (the one that was in today) off. Sweet! I can now go back to accepting all cash sent my way, provided it's actual, legal tender. I understand I work a stupid, minimum wage job. I understand not everyone here has the minimum intelligence needed to sort fake bills from real ones. However, I still feel bad turning people away just because their legitimate bills are too large.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

How did the Free Software Foundation find me!?

Day 00835: Monday, 2017 June 19

General news

How did the Free Software Foundation find me!? I stopped donating to them at least three years ago, have since moved thrice, and have never given them this address. Now, I receive a letter in the mail begging for another donation. They don't seem to have my current name, only my birth name. I don't recall ever giving them that either, but whatever; they can have that. I need to figure out how they're tracking me though.

I forgot to update my whois records to reflect my legal name change. I've done this now today though, so everything should now be in order.

I finally finished unpacking my clothing into my closet. It's been pretty low on my priority list, but I finally got around to it so I could deal with my sock situation. I've also thrown out all my pairs of underwear that have holes at the waistband and replaced them. I still have some with small holes elsewhere, but those seem much less likely to quickly continue degrading. As for my sock situation I mentioned ... I was considering throwing out all my socks and replacing them with two styles of socks; one black, one white. It'd be so easy to match socks then, I wouldn't even need to worry about slightly-mismatched socks ever again. I decided against that plan by the end of the day though. It'd be a huge waste, and then I'd be stuck with no variety anyway. I just need to get a bunch of those sock clips that keep socks sorted even in the wash. I wonder where I can find those ... Speaking of socks, I think that's what I'll put in that crate my neighbour gave me. First though, I'll need to get those clips and sort out any socks with holes in them. Every sock in the crate will be clipped to a mate, and any without a mate will be thrown out. I've moved several times in the recent past, so there's a high probability those sock mates are gone for good.

I was shown the website of another agendered person with a self-chosen name and a short domain name: Sai. Unlike me though, they chose "Sai" as their only name, while I chose "Yst" as my surname. I don't want to stand out too much, at least not for now. I identify by the name "Yst" much more then by "Alex" or "Alex Yst", but the name "Alex" helps me not look like a total nut job. At least, that's my intent. Maybe one day, I'll change my name again and drop the "Alex" ... but for now, I'm contented with the way things are now. That said, I've got a lot of possible nicknames if I keep "Alex", some of which are pretty nice, such as "Lexi" and "Xander". I also don't want to totally lose my identity if something horrible happens and I lose my domain somehow. As it is now, I'd only lose the meaning of half my name, so I'd only have to replace half my name. If something terrible happens, it could be useful having my name be partially decoupled from my domain name, but at the same time, my domain name is a huge part of who I am and I don't want my personal name and my domain name to be completely decoupled.

I used to be a little off-put when I was given items personalised with my name. However, I'm starting to realise that was only because I hated my name. Now, I enjoy seeing things with my name on them, even if they're not my things. It's hard to describe the feeling, but the closest I can come at the moment is that it amuses me slightly.

I was thinking about my login name at University of [REDACTED] today. Instead of using something memorable, they have us log in using our student numbers. It seems impersonal, but at the same time, the alternative would probably be to log in using a derivative of our legal names. Had the system been set up that way, I'd likely be stuck logging in using my birth name, even now. That'd really suck.

One of my coworkers asked me if I've ever experienced a "ghost burn" before. Um ... a what? It turns out they were referring to the phenomenon of touching the table and being burnt by it despite no obvious heat source. I can't seem to find any legitimacy to the term, but it's caused by setting a hot pan on the table and later removing it, forgetting that it had been set there. The pan heats the table, then you burn yourself on the table. I've done that loads of times, though I didn't have a name for it. "Ghost burn" does sound pretty cool though, so I'm just going to go with that.

One of my bosses grabbed the three keys dangling around my neck, looking them over. They said "apartment key, mail key, ..." and just sort of trailed off, not sure what the third key was. It's just the laundry room key, but I told them it was the key to my heart. They said that they'd get someone to steal it from me, so I replied that I'd change the locks. They said you can't change the locks on your heart, so I retorted that I know a good heart surgeon slash lock smith. They didn't have much to say on the matter after that, but admitted that those are hard to come by.

My coworker whose shift I covered about a week ago was grateful. They apparently needed the day off to study for a big test, and passed it. The offered me a haircut for my trouble or a caffeinated beverage, but I passed. I'm growing my hair out now, and I don't drink caffeine. Besides, their gratitude is enough. Well, that and the money I made just for picking up those extra hours.

One of my other coworkers said they're jealous of my surname. I told them they could have it too if they want to go to court for it. They don't want to pay the court fees though, and I don't blame them. More than getting my new name, I wanted to be rid of the birth name name I hated, so it was worth it for me. It's not something that's worth it for everyone. It turns out my coworker also liked my birth surname too. I guess that name wasn't terrible, it was just my given and middle names I didn't like. Still, if I was going to pay the court fees, take the time to figure out how to change my name, and go through the stress of changing my name legally for the first time ... I might as well get the most out of it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The credit union branch is closing, I'm still recovering from potential mould-poisoning, and I now have a task list from the local, public library.

Day 00838: Thursday, 2017 June 22

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up my bedroom

Finish file-sorting
Finish sock-sorting
Clear off the shelf in my closet
Finish hanging my work clothing

Clean up the study alcove and living room
Clean up the kitchen and entryway

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a nonfiction title
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a book checked out from the Springfield Library (print, ebook, or audio)
Visit somewhere new in downtown Springfield
Read a graphic novel
Read an author you have never read before
Get outside: read in a Willamalane park for one hour willamalane.org
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Read a book from a library display
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Build community: do something social. Try one of our book groups or go to Springfilm!
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country
Recommend our BINGO challenge to friends or family

General news

My stomach still aches today, so I didn't feel like getting much done. I thought it might be my abs from the workout I did on my break yesterday, but I'm starting to fear for my health. I was not doing well before I headed into work yesterday. In case this is just muscle soreness, I skipped my morning sit-ups. If it's my muscles, then the sooner they get some rest, the sooner I can set my mind at ease.

Last time I worked on sorting my files, I got a huge chunk of the sorting done. I jumped right into trying to put each file where it belonged, and I removed files to be shredded as I went. Since then though, I haven't stayed organised, and I've acquired a lot of new papers. This time, I started by gathering all my paperwork to the same place, then instead of sortin it to where it belonged, simply sorting it into what I wanted to keep and what I could shred. Anything I from the banks I had an account with in Coos Bay, almost everything from my old school, past notifications from Discover and Oregon Community Credit Union that are no longer relevant, old letters from politicians addressed to my birth name, junk mail that was never filed but was brought into my collection when I gathered my papers ... all of that could just be shredded. Next time I work on this, I'll have a smaller, more meaningful paperwork pile to deal with. I need to avoid holding onto junk mail too, and dispose of that right away.

A lot of these things don't theoretically need to be shredded, but the way I see it, it's like using Tor. If only those that absolutely need it use it; and even then, only when they have something to hide; it's easier to find the secret traffic. At that point, focus can be directed to cracking the contents of that traffic. It's anything coming from an exit node! But if everyone uses Tor all the time, it becomes incredibly easy to blend in and remain private. If I shred all papers I'm recycling, sorting out the juicy account numbers and such becomes more difficult.

I did a little sock-sorting, but not any noticeable amount. I figure if I do at least a little sock-sorting and at least a little file-sorting each day, I'll get done at some point without having to spend all day on either project.

I received two emails from Discover, one saying my new card will arrive tomorrow, the other saying it'll come the next day. I'm assuming they didn't mess up and send two cards. Soon I'll have the new one and I can shred the old one with my old, stupid name on it.

I went to the public library to check on the expiration status of my old library card I've had since before I moved to Coos Bay. I was hoping it had expired so I could get it replaced with one under my current name. It turns out it was set to expire next month, and they've extended the expiration date now. Instead of issuing me a new card, they just updated my name in their database, then had me sign my new signature over my faded signature on the card. In general, this is a good idea as it saves plastic, so I shouldn't be too disappointed, but it'd be nice to be rid of objects that needlessly have my old name on them.

While at the library, the librarian talked me into taking a "bingo" sheet of activities to complete. At first, I was reluctant. I'm very busy and don't have time for added activities. On the other hand though, some of these could be a chance to meet new people and make friends. Additionally, the wording on some of these allow for interpretation that doesn't require me to do much extra. Most of them that involve books don't specifically mention requiring the books come from the library. I'd assume that requirement was a given, if not for the "Read a book checked out from the Springfield Library (print, ebook, or audio)" task. That task pretty much admits none of the others that don't specifically mention the books needing to be checked out from the library actually have that requirement. I can therefore use my school textbooks in some cases. Lastly, some of these will involve getting the help of a librarian. Librarian help is offered and I don't know what I'm doing with their systems. Networking with the librarians a bit could play in my favour later when I try to talk them into acting as a proctor for some of my university courses. Honestly, I mostly took the day off today. I didn't feel well and I wanted rest. However, if I mostly stay ahead of my coursework, I might be able to work all these tasks into my schedule. The worst task might be "Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)" because of its length and lack of flexibility. Any work that recent will be under copyright, so I can't do what I'll do for most of the other tasks and either use a textbook I was going to read anyway or choose a book I can actually recommend to people. That said, I might be able to find a CC BY-SA book or something. "Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody" is even more inflexible as far as copyright-dodging, but poems don't tend to take days to read, so I'm not too worried about that one. And "Visit somewhere new in downtown Springfield"? I've never been to the Springfield visitor's centre, though I've been meaning to go see what's in there. Some of these books I'll have to read won't be for school, but I can't do anything useful on my breaks at work anyway. I can't read textbooks, because I need my computer set up while I read so I can take proper notes, especially for the learning journal assignments. I can use that time to read library books. This list of copyright expiration years will come in handy when choosing books.

I also checked in with First Tech Federal Credit Union to get my account updated there. I've got to say, that was the easiest account to get updated. Chase is still giving me trouble. Discover wanted me to upload proof, but when their site wouldn't let me, they named me copy my documents and mail them in. Oregon Community Credit Union folded my certified copy of the decree. Both Discover and Oregon Community made me wait for my new card in the mail, and Chase will do the same if I can get them to eventually figure out to change my name in their records. The First Tech representative just glanced over my court decree and ID though, then printed out a new debit card in-house and handed it to me. I'm not saying that having to wait for the card in the mail is terrible by any means, but the simple fact is that First Tech didn't make me wait at all (aside from, like, a ten-minute wait in their lobby for a representative). Everything is just done with, and that's kind of cool.

Later in the day, I checked the mail and found my new Discover card. Sweet! Now I can shred my old one; at least the one with my birth name on it, though not the one under the name "Yst Dawson". It's unlikely that one will come in handy, but it might. That's one less trinket for me to hold onto with my birth name on it. I also got a letter from First Tech though. They're closing their Springfield branch. I'm going to need to withdraw my money and close the account before that happens. My trip there to get my account updated was for nothing.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

I've decided to try a little experiment. Okay, it's a big experiment. I've decided to throw out as many assumptions about myself as I can. I've been changing over the past while, and I may be growing into a truer version of me. Certain assumptions about myself are easy to reestablish. Do I still believe in free software? Check. The logic on that is still sound. Do I still enjoy chiptune with instrumentals and vocals thrown in? Check. Professor Shyguy's still awesome. Some things though ... my place in the world, deeper parts about who and what I am ... they'll take time to figure out, and the answers may or may not be what I think. I'm dumping most of the labels I've branded myself with, simply because I need to know if they truly fit me. I'm hoping to get certain labels back, but even if I don't, at least I won't be under the impression that I am what I'm not.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm dying ...

Day 00840: Saturday, 2017 June 24

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up my bedroom

Finish file-sorting
Finish sock-sorting
Finish hanging my work clothing

Clean up the study alcove and living room
Clean up the kitchen and entryway

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a nonfiction title
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a book checked out from the Springfield Library (print, ebook, or audio)
Visit somewhere new in downtown Springfield
Read a graphic novel
Read an author you have never read before
Get outside: read in a Willamalane park for one hour willamalane.org
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Read a book from a library display
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Build community: do something social. Try one of our book groups or go to Springfilm!
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country
Recommend our BINGO challenge to friends or family

General news

I wrote back to Chase:

I just received the new form you sent in the mail. It's identical to the old one you sent! It says only to fill it out if my name change was *not* because of a court order, but my name change *was* because of a court order.

It also says to bring proof of my name change into a branch, but I *already did that*. You then sent me via post a letter saying no change was needed because my name was already up to date in your records. However, the mere fact that you keep addressing me as "[REDACTED]" is proof that my name in your records isn't up to date. My name is Alex Yst, and I've already had an in-branch representative fax you proof of that. How do I get you to actually update my account?

Let's see how they respond to that.

I took care of my voter registration today. It'll take time to make it through the mail, but once it does, I'll be that much closer to being able to finish shredding outdated files. I think the last of the files in my shred-but-not-yet pile are the letters from Chase about the name change, my old voter registration cards from past and current addresses under my old name, and everything I have left from First Tech. I thought about finishing up with First Tech today, but there just wasn't time. Instead, I wanted to finish up the cleaning of my bedroom. Technically, it's all clean now, but I've moved my unsorted socks to the living room to get them out of the way, and I'm still calling those a bedroom task. They're all I have left to do in here though; next, I'll probably focus on the living room and study alcove. Some of the stuff out there needs to come back into the bedroom but in a neater fashion. I'm also converting the study alcove into a sort of guest room. I may never have anyone stay over, but it gives me a place to put my other mattress, and I have no purpose for that room. There's no lights over there even, so I can't actually use it to study in or set up a desk and computer.

One of my shift leader's offered me a filing cabinet given to the head manager. It seems the head manager doesn't thing it's a good fit for the office, and was considering taking it home themself. So ... why did the shift leader offer it to me then? I rode my bike to work as usual today though, so getting the cabinet home would be a pain. I left it there to pick up tomorrow. This one actually has keys, too, unlike my other one! The one I already have has a lock, but the keys were lost by a previous owner.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

As I continued reading the book I checked out, I came across the thoughts of a homosexual person from when they were growing up. They felt that they were wrong, a freak, a mistake. When I was a child, I always felt like I was a mistake of nature, that I should never have existed. I guess I didn't feel like a freak; it was more like there was no place for me. Like ... there wasn't anything different about me than about normal people, but that my very existence was somehow ... not right. This was long before I understood that I *was* in fact different. It makes me wonder if those of use that are different can somehow sense it. We might not get the exact nature of our freakhood right (at least I didn't), but maybe it's not too uncommon to feel something isn't quite right; or rather, that something isn't quite *normal* about us.

Mental health watch

I was thinking to myself today that it shouldn't matter if I'm not as productive in the world as I could be, or if I go crazy. As long as I do as little harm as I can, I should be free to do whatever makes *me* happy. Finding a mate wouldn't be so bad ... That's when it hit me. I'm succumbing to the madness! I'm losing my objectivity and actually considering the possibility of finding a partner! That's when I realised it was my real self that even pointed out the fact I'm losing my sanity. The real me ... I can feel it dying. As I realised this, I began to literally cry a bit. Most likely, the real me will cease to be in the near future, yet it's too late. As I write this, I'm crying again, knowing it's too late to save me. Those sexual thoughts have come back, but this time, more subtly, more slowly. This time, they got me with my guard down, they consumed too much of me. There's not enough of the real me to even fight back now, and I'll be going along with this and seeing where it takes me. My final hope is that I remain lucid in my madness. If I'm aware, maybe I won't actually disappear. Maybe I can be happy as this new me, while not forgetting that this new me is bat-shit crazy. I think ... I think I could enjoy that. It's likely that these mental health watch sections won't last much longer though. As I go insane, it's likely I'll forget I'm insane at all. That would, of course, mean the real me will have died after all.

However, it's worth noting that if this really is some sexuality bubbling to the surface, it's reversed polarity from last time. Previously, I was favouring one sex over the other, but now, I seem to be favouring the other one. One of my coworkers of that sex was using my register today, so I had to wait for them to finish before ringing my customer up. I enjoyed looking at the back of their neck. I'd never pursue them, they're married, but it feels like a sign of a change in me. My fantasies have reversed too, and involve only life partners of this sex.

It's possible these are only fantasies and nothing more. It's true I found the back of my coworker's neck attractive. However, there was zero intent in any direction behind it. I didn't want to date my coworker, or bed them. I'm freaking out a bit, but this might not actually lead anywhere; it sure didn't last time.

I've decided I need to get out of here, or at least try. I need to try to get a more-reasonable job. There's too much to tackle at once right now, so I won't look right away. I've got my apartment-cleaning spree, my library challenge, work, and school ... Once I get my apartment cleaned up though, I'll probably start to job hunt. I don't have my degree yet, but it can't hurt to try.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

♪ Forever, that is me. 🎵

Day 00842: Monday, 2017 June 26

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up my bedroom

Finish sock-sorting

Clean up the study alcove and living room
Clean up the kitchen and entryway

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a nonfiction title
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a book checked out from the Springfield Library (print, ebook, or audio)
Visit somewhere new in downtown Springfield
Read a graphic novel
Read an author you have never read before
Get outside: read in a Willamalane park for one hour willamalane.org
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Read a book from a library display
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Build community: do something social. Try one of our book groups or go to Springfilm!
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country
Recommend our BINGO challenge to friends or family

General news

I went to First Tech to close my account and mention the website issue. They asked if a cashier's cheque would be alright for the withdrawal. I always prefer cash, but as I was just going to run it over to Oregon Community Credit Union right away, it didn't particularly matter, so I let them give me the cheque instead. My money is now consolidated in one place, becoming whole, like the fragments of my fractured mind. Strangely, when the teller ran my coins through their counting machine, they found an odd, bent quarter. They showed it to one of their coworkers, and I thought it was the odd penny I've had for a while. Coin counters usually won't count it because it's bizarrely too large to be a penny. It couldn't be counterfeit though, could it? No one would waste their money creating coins that are worth less than the metal they're made from. My best guess is that it was the victim of a chemical reaction, as in addition to the size oddity, the metal composition seems off. It wasn't the penny though, the counter took that. They gave me the quarter, not knowing what else to do with it, as the counter wouldn't count a bent coin. I was amused, and said the counting machine must've bent it. If I'd had a bent coin in my coin pouch, I'd've noticed it. As I was walking out though, I realised that the quarter hadn't been mine. I don't keep quarters in the coin pouch. I use that pouch specifically for coins I plan to put in a credit union account. I keep my quarters on my shelf though to feed the washing machines and dryers.

Depending on the route I took, Bi-Mart would be on the way home, so I headed in their direction. I had planned to try to register a new card with them for their lucky number Tuesday, but I decided today that I might not like the consequences of my attempt at deception. I lent my old card to Cyrus long ago, who lost it. The truth is, I'm not going to be doubling my odds of winning by getting another card, I'm just going to be getting back to the regular odds; my odds for the time being have been zero. They always check ID before allowing registration though. I thought they might have my ID number on file, so I instead admitted I lost the card long ago and asked if there was any way for me to get a replacement. Their system is nowhere near as sophisticated as I feared though. They checked my ID, but couldn't find the surname "Yst" on file. Unable to proceed in any way, I asked if, since I clearly didn't have a membership on file, I could register a new one. They had no reason to disallow it, so I now have a Bi-Mart membership that has never been attached to my former name.

This wound on my hand is painful and annoying. It looks like it's doing better. I really should be more careful. Still though, there's no reason the front counter at work should have that long, metal tab sticking up. The only thing it does is provide a hazard.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was at work, and someone ordered fourteen taquitoes. We don't have those on our menu, but one of the shift leaders had brought some in to cook and eat. I asked if they wanted to sell them, they reluctantly agreed, saying they didn't want to be stingy. It turned out the number we had was the exact number the customer wanted. I was going to sell them for a dollar each, then give the money to the shift leader that had given them up, but I decided to be sure on the price first. I asked, and they said fifty cents instead. After cooking them, I got to the window, and the person ordering them drove off in a rush without taking them or paying for them.

It turned out to be a former coworker of mine. They knew very well we don't sell taquitoes, and had ordered them as a prank. Then when we actually *had* them, they didn't *want* them. I stared at my former coworker in the distance trying to decide what to do, but a group of nearby punks didn't like my staring in their direction (my coworker was far behind them), and they came over to the window to mess with me. They stole a dollar and a half of the money that was for some reason on the counter instead of in the register. I managed to pull the dollar from their grasp, but there was no hope in getting close enough to pry the quarters away from them, so I didn't even try. I then noticed they had some of our paperwork, so I snatched that back as well. It hadn't been filled out yet, so we could've reprinted it, but I didn't like these thieves taking our stuff. Besides, they were only taking the paperwork to mess with me, they did't have a use for it.

I went to tell the shift leader about our former coworker's prank, the fact that we still had the taquitoes, and the fact that we'd lost fifty cents to thieving punks. After doing so, one of the walls opened up and revealed a secret freezer section. Somehow though, this belonged to Fred Meyer, so only Fred Meyer employees were allowed in. Cyrus was now with us, which was particularly strange, as we were in the back room of my workplace, where only our employees are allowed, and we'd somehow intersected with Fred Meyers, so a Fred Meyers employee was there too, but there was no reason for a random person from outside these places of employment to be there. Cyrus brushed my neck with his hand or something; I forget the exact reason. All I remember is that it hurt, as he came in contact with a tender skin tag there. When I reacted, he thought he'd been too rough, so I showed him the skin tag and he understood.

Now that I'm awake, I see the skin tag is very much there, but it's not tender in any way. It's one of several I'v had on my neck line for quite a while.

Mental health watch

I just realised this morning that I can't be demihomosexual. I can't be demisexual of any flavour. Simply put, even though I'm not experiencing desire, I'm still experiencing sexual attraction. I might be full-on homosexual, but I'm not demi-anything. The question of if I have enough sexuality or pair-bonding instinct in me to actually attempt to find relationship partner remains to be seen though. Finding a partner without trying likely won't happen. I have too many uncommon quirks, such as my veganism and demand for free software. I can't live with non-vegan products in the house, and I *won't* live with Windows machines in my abode. That said, if I actually *did* try ... there's got to be someone like me; several someones, actually. It should be possible to track one down that loves me, and that I love them. I'm getting ahead of myself though.

I'm convinced my past self is attached to my past name. The majority of the larger changes in my mental state only occurred after I cleared myself of that ridiculous name. I think that name was one of the major lynchpins that kept me in that state of mind. That state of mind was more practical than my current one, but also more neurotic and in a constant state of frustration. As [REDACTED] dies away, I feel Alex becoming stronger, more confident, and more relaxed. I even found myself singing a little song today:

🎶 I'm Alex Yst forever. 𝆕
🎜 Forever, forever. ♬
♫ I'm Alex Yst forever. 🎝
♪ Forever, that is me. 🎵

At work, I was stationed at the oven landing with my martial artist shift leader. Near the end of the day, they said again that they'd find someone to take that key I'd previously told them was the key to my heart. The continued that they didn't know if my heart was broken, but they'd find someone to break it. I refuse to live in a closet, so I admitted what's been going on lately: that I think my heart is healing, and that I've been experiencing sexual attraction. Also, that I might be homosexual. It turns out they're bisexual, so that put them firmly in the camp of understanding. They're not heteronormative. We talked a bit, and I think in having to formulate sentences, I crystallised my thoughts on the matter. My biggest frustration is that I don't want to be this. I don't want to be gay, or strait, or bi. I want to be ace, like I've always been. On top of that though, I don't even know if I'm going to be this next week. My last strange hormone surge went away; my hormones may still be in flux and I may yet return to normal (well, normal for me). If I'm stuck gay though, how do I even know who's gay and not? Who can I even pursue without making feel uncomfortable?

Lastly, the man I've most been attracted to so far is a married strait man. He's certainly not going to be interested in me. Ha, if he found out, he'd probably be weirded out. He's funny though, and handsome. That said, in all honesty, he's not right for me. He has children, which means he *would* have children. That's not the type of person I'd want to spend my life with. The world's overpopulated already, so someone that wants to push the child issue is going to make me as unhappy as I'd make them. He's also clever, but I don't think he's super geeky or anything. He likely wouldn't understand my computerised interests. He's knowledgeable about pop culture, so he's probably into that, while I shun all things nonfree. We have, like, nothing in common, besides the desire to joke around and keep the workplace lighthearted. Oh, yeah, I just remembered he's not vegan. We wouldn't work out at all as a couple.

A couple paragraphs back, I mentioned the healing of my heart, and elsewhere in this journal entry, I mentioned my fractured mind becoming whole as of late. I think my previous living environment was more toxic than I realised. I was never free to be me, so whatever I was, it was just my mind's way of defending itself from onslaught. As I learn to love and accept myself for who I am, my mind is exposing itself and showing me who I am. The previous case of my sexuality coming out then going away again could be because I didn't accept that part of me yet. I'd accepted enough of me to expose the next part, but when I found that part of me to be vile, it hid again. I likely can't discover the rest of me until I accept and embrace this part; the part that might not want to live and die alone. It could take time though, as I've always considered this sort of pairing to be a symptom of weakness. Do I really need to be strong though? Do I owe that to *anyone*, myself included? I think that, perhaps, I don't. In the name of science (or rather, self-discovery), I must press onward.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Proving I'm me when I want to

Day 00843: Tuesday, 2017 June 27

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the study alcove and living room
Clean up the kitchen and entryway

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a nonfiction title
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a book checked out from the Springfield Library (print, ebook, or audio)
Visit somewhere new in downtown Springfield
Read a graphic novel
Read an author you have never read before
Get outside: read in a Willamalane park for one hour willamalane.org
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Read a book from a library display
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Build community: do something social. Try one of our book groups or go to Springfilm!
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country
Recommend our BINGO challenge to friends or family

General news

I had my filing cabinet key copied this morning. Again, the locksmith asked for ID when I tried to pay with my credit card. This time though, I actually had ID to show them. It's a nice feeling being able to prove who I am when I want to.

My mother wrote today asking if I was home. I took this as a threat that she was coming over. I switched from coursework mode to mad-rush apartment-cleaning mode. I'm getting so much closer to having the place presentable, but it's not there yet. As it turned out, she had just come over to dump trash in the apartment dumpster and was thinking about how she hadn't seen me in a while. With my recent hormonal issues, coursework, and lack of organisation, I haven't had time to visit. I admitted the first two of these things to her. I wasn't sure what to expect from her, but as I said yesterday, I refuse to live in a closet. I never got to come out of the closet as an asexual, as I was open all along. Part of that was likely due to the fact that I didn't understand that everyone else wasn't like me. By the time I had a label for it, I'd been out all along. The only difference here is that now I know. I recognise I'm not like the others and I already have what I think is the right label for it. I can't hide though. My self-exploration demands that I admit what I am; otherwise, the next part of me likely won't reveal itself. In any case, my mother seemed pretty accepting, offering two possibilities. First, she said even "normal" (quotes added by me, not her) guys have gay thoughts, even if they don't admit it. If that's the case, I could still be asexual, I'm just having normal, strange thoughts. The second is that I might be a late bloomer, as my sexuality never seemed to expose itself as a child. I've considered this possibility. Several times. I'm not sure I like this option, but if it does turn out to be the case, I might just need a handsome man in my life.

I was no longer in the mood to do coursework. I was already in mad-rush apartment-cleaning mode, so I continued with that for a bit. I've completely cleaned out the study alcove, and I've organised most of the stuff in the living room. What remains is a small pile; small enough that saying that the mess is only temporary while I finish organising the place is actually believable now. I've likewise cleaned up the entryway, including the shelves built into the wall there, and have started on the kitchen. Once this place is fully-organised, surprise visits won't be such a threat any more.

I had a passing thought today. I thought that homophobia was the fear that one might be gay themself, but often resulted in discrimination against homosexuals as a form of self-reassurance. I mean, if you hate gays, you can't be one yourself, right? I don't hate gays; one of my best friends in high school was gay. I'm just not sure I want to *be* gay. So does my fear that I might be gay make me homophobic? I looked it up though, and while the internalised version (as opposed to the institutionalised version) of homophobia does stem from a fear that one might themself be gay, homophobia is about negativity towards homosexuality. I have no problem with homosexuality. To me, homosexuality is like neckties. I don't want to wear them myself, but I honestly have no problem with other people wearing them. I find wearing neckties to be an unpleasant thought, as I find them uncomfortable, but other people find them to be very handsome and/or stylish, and that's fine too.

The wound on my left palm continues to noticeably shrink, but I'm still impatient for it to heal up completely. If I could've hurt some other part of my body that I don't use to grab everything, that'd've been more convenient. The scar on my right thumb from crashing my bicycle over a year ago still hasn't gone away. I guess that one might be permanent. Long story short, don't bike at night without bike lights unless there are plenty of street lights. I mean, uh, don't bike at night without bike lights, 'cause that's illegal. Yeah, that's what I meant to say.

It seems that within the next week or two, we're remodelling the front counter and lobby at work. My martial artist shift leader said it's likely we'll remove the stupid, dangerous counter I hurt my hand on. Score! I ... have doubts as to whether this'll actually happen though. We've remodelled before, and always left that counter. I don't want to get my hopes up too far.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

At work, I tried to keep an eye on what physical features I find attractive. I'm new at this, so honestly, I don't know what I like. Looks aren't everything, and I think I'd partner with an ugly guy if he had a good heart, but it doesn't hurt to know what you're into. Besides, part of accepting who I am is exploring this. Anyway, I found something very interesting to me. While my main attraction seems to be toward males, I'm having some attraction toward females with certain masculine characteristics. That is, until I think about genitals. Female genitals are a huge turn-off for me, while a penis against my prostate actually sounds pretty fun. Interesting. I'm also noticing that my attractions aren't coming with any desire. Sex with people I don't know, or even people I do, isn't overly appealing. I want one man that I can trust and wrap myself around. It seems I'm not promiscuous then. That's good; sex with one person is a risk, but sex with a multitude is just asking for trouble. Another thing that might make being gay a better fit for my personality (not that I have a choice in the matter), is that traditional gender roles in a gay relation ship hold little meaning. There is no woman to fill feminine roles and no man to fill masculine roles. We'll be just two men, defining our roles together.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Monogamy instinct

Day 00845: Thursday, 2017 June 29

General news

As an asexual, I had no idea what wanting to be monogamous is like. Now that I know I'm gay, it's like ... I want someone I can fully dedicate myself to, and who'll be fully dedicated to me. I want someone I can trust with all my heart and I want him to be able to trust me fully as well. This feeling is incredibly strange to me and will take time to get used to. I had no idea that the monogamy instinct was even a thing until now.

I went to visit my mother today. Vanessa asked how I was, so I brought her up to speed on this gayness thing. Our mother may or may not've told her already, I'm not sure. While we were discussing my new-found sexuality, I mentioned I was finding all sorts of new things, such as that monogamy instinct. I honestly thought my mother would claim it wasn't an instinct, but just a desire, but she seemed to know exactly what I meant. She said that when in a relationship, she doesn't tend to even notice other people. They're not even attractive to her. So ... that's something I can look forward to. Once I have a partner, I won't have to resist other people, as there likely won't be any attraction for me to resist. My mother also had an idea of why I might not've know I was a sexual until now. I thought she might ask me why I thought it was, which I didn't want to explain, so I was glad she had her own theory. She thinks I'm a late bloomer because of genetics. She says she didn't really feel the urges until beyond her teens, while my father has no sex drive. The average of the two would ... maybe be me. It seems ... plausible, but doesn't match up with quite all the data. Then again, my mother doesn't *have* all the data, so it doesn't need to. That just means it's not going to be the theory I subscribe to. As suspected though, my mother's sort of happy I'm gay. She never did like that I wasn't attracted to anyone at all.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

I feel ... calm, today. I mean, part of it's that I'm all cried out, I'm sure. It's hard to feel such strong, negative emotions for so long. My brain's probably temporarily shut part of my emotion centre off, and I'm very tired. At the same time though, my libido seems mostly back to normal. I'm not so constantly horny any more. I think the horniness was my brain's way of forcing me to pay attention. It has my attention now, and I'm examining the way that I feel and what I'm becoming. My brain probably feels the mental and emotional healing, so the call to attention is no longer necessary and has been shut off. I think my hormones are returning to manageable levels.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

So this is loneliness ...

Day 00846: Friday, 2017 June 30

General news

I was in the laundry room checking on my clothing in the dryer, and a pair of people came to drop off a printer at the giveaway table. Of course, I took it up to my room to investigate it. It didn't seem to be compatible with my machine at first, but I did a quick Web search to see if there was any information on if this printer model was known to be or not be compatible with Debian. I didn't find anything specific, but I did find a webpage telling me to install cups to make Canon printers in general function. It also told me to install some other things, but those were already on my system apparently. Additionally, there were other steps, but none of them were even needed in my case. All had to do was install cups. Well that was easy. I think I now have a working printer! It needs ink and paper though, of which I have neither. At some point, I'll look into what kind of cartridges it takes.

Chase sent me a third copy (or is it fourth now, I forget) of that stupid form that tells me not to fill it out. I'm starting to get very peeved with Chase at this point.

Yesterday, my mother left me a bunch of their old paperwork to shred. I got a lot of it shredded today, but it was kind of hard on the shredder. It stopped functioning after a while. The motor runs, but the blades don't turn. I dismantled the thing, and there are physical cracks on the inside now. One plastic tab is broken off entirely. That's the first break I saw, and I thought I might be able to make the thing work anyway. The second and third cracks though ... look like they're somewhere more important. The plastic containment around the blades is broken. I fear that if I get the thing working again, it won't be safe to actually use. Drats. I guess I'm without a shredder for now then.

At work, my fatigue was easily visible on my face, so a few of my coworkers asked how I was doing. I explained my story. Only one shift leader thought to even ask me which sex I'm falling for though, making the total number of coworkers that now know only two. I want it to be known, but at the same time, I don't want it to be some big announcement. I tried dropping various hints, but I don't think anyone caught on. They'll know soon enough though. I feel a bit bare without my asexuality ring. I need to replace it with something, like a rainbow wristband. Then I can feel a bit more like me and a bit less hidden.

It seems my new friend at work likes Kellee Maize's music. Nice! It's hard to find people that even recognise any of the music I listen to. Free culture artists don't get as much exposure as they deserve.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I had an incredibly bizarre dream. I only remember the last bit though. Some weird shit had been going on before that though. Someone mentioned having conquered their own identity and taken control of it. They meant they understood who they were and were in control of how others perceived them. The other person, who was highly secretive, said that the first had no idea what conquering one's own identity even meant. I then saw inside this second person's mind as they thought about their own identity. As I looked around in their mind, I saw every piece of their identity had been narrowed down to two pieces of data: a word and a number. I remember neither, now that I'm awake. But their address, their name, and I forget what other specifics ... they *all* matched. Every single thing about them matched, if it had a name and/or number to it. They'd manipulated their own lives so *all* this information would be the same. Why would they do that!? At first, it felt like it had something to do with keeping mind readers from being able to read them as well. A mind reader would be confused when all they could see was these two scraps of information. And that's when the person noticed me looking into their minds. At first, I thought this whole thing was fabricated; they'd focused on this fake identity hard enough as to keep me from knowing who they were. But their words made me think otherwise. "I forgot you'd be here, Vanessa." I was this Vanessa person; someone sharing a name with my real-world sister, I guess. However, they hadn't been conjuring this image for me. They'd really lived their life with such control that aside from these two scraps of information, there wasn't anything else to their identity. Just the same two strings, everywhere in different forms. The number was sometimes in Roman numerals, but it was always the same number. They then expelled me from their mind, mentally conjuring some blob at the point I was visually seeing through and sending it toward my vision further. It spasmed and writhed rapidly as it came at my non-existent body, ostensibly to spook this Vanessa person into dropping the connection to their mind. Instead, the combined shock of their core identity and this blob caused me to wake up.

As I write this, I'm crying. I have no idea why, but I'm crying. I have no idea what the dream means, but ... are these tears of fear? From beginning to end, tears rolled down my face as I recounted the dream fragment in text, though after finishing, I was fine. That is, until I went back and reread the dream, then I started crying again. What does this mean?

Mental health watch

Based on my inability to love romantically, I've always said I only have half a heart. I guess somewhere amongst the pieces of my broken self, I found the other half. But my mind is in a less-fractured state than before. I should feel more whole, more complete. So why do I feel *less* complete? Why do I feel like I need someone to complete me? This makes me feel powerless and inadequate. I started feeling what I believe to be loneliness for the first time in my life today. I thought I'd been lonely once before, but now I think what I felt before was some variant of boredom. This new feeling ... it's like an aching in my chest, between where I think my stomach and heart are, along with a strong yearning for a man I can wrap myself around. It's highly distracting and annoying. I can easily see why most people try to pair up.

I've also come to realise that [REDACTED] is still alive and well, and likely will be for the foreseeable future. He was never an outer shell constructed to protect what was left of my psyche as I'd previously thought. He was what *remained intact* of my psyche. It was harder to hurt [REDACTED] due to how little of him there was. Alex is a boulder; [REDACTED] is a grain of sand. Which one can you chip away at? As I piece myself back together, Alex grows stronger because there's more of them. [REDACTED] only appears to grow weaker out of comparison to Alex's strength. One thing you have to remember is that Alex can never be weaker than [REDACTED], as [REDACTED] is *a part of* Alex. [REDACTED] is being drown out almost entirely, which is why he no longer has much control. He doesn't seem to be fully integrated with the larger chunk of me though, as he still has separate thoughts to interject on occasion, thoughts that are decidedly his and not the thoughts of Alex as a whole. Eventually, he should settle in and reintegrate.

I've also come to think I might be bisexual like Vanessa, once fully healed. Previously, I was noticing people of both sexes. I was scared by this, then I started preferring *women*. Having a preference scared me further, then it all went away. I went back to being completely asexual. Soon, my sexuality returned, but this time, I was gay. I think I was more ready to accept having a man in my life than a woman. In a same-sex couple, a breach of trust could be detrimental to myself. However, in an opposite-sex relationship, a breach of trust could result in a baby, which would be detrimental to the world. The worst part is that I'd've been a part of it. Honestly, some part of me fears sabotaged or failed condoms. I'm not the woman, so I can't make sure an abortion happens. Even if we agree beforehand that an abortion is absolutely necessary if something goes wrong, she could change her mind and I'd have no remedy. I'd hate myself if I let this happen, but at the same time, I don't want to mutilate my body for sterilisation. Likewise, if the woman mutilated *her* body to become sterile, I would feel she had less respect for herself than I have for myself, and would be an unsuitable partner for me. There simply is no way to win without a leap of trust, and if I took that leap, I could lose big time. I'm not yet ready to even *think* about any heterosexual relationships. At some point though, I'll need to revisit this and figure out if I'm actually bi. For now, I think accepting the gay part is enough to move on and gather other pieces of my mind for reintegration. After all, there are emotions and such that this unlocks that I can now process. I never actually wanted a relationship with a woman though, I only was seeing their attraction. It's still possible I'm fully gay.

I spent the past few days listening to proprietary music that happened to be about being gay. I shouldn't be listening to proprietary garbage, but I think it helped my gayness sink in. Now that I'm more accepting of my current state, I started listening to healthy, free music again. It would be nice if I could find some free, gay songs though. The only love/sex songs I have are decidedly heterosexual.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.